<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on joesacher.com</title>
    <link>http://www.joesacher.com/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on joesacher.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2002-2017 - Joe Sacher - All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.joesacher.com/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing for Pizza by John Grisham</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2011/08/02/playing-for-pizza-by-john-grisham/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2011/08/02/playing-for-pizza-by-john-grisham/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit that I was intrigued when I read the summary of this book. A novel by John Grisham about a third string NFL quarterback, escaping his terrible past to play professional football in Italy. Nothing about lawyers? This sounds interesting, if not just to figure out why John didn&amp;rsquo;t write about lawyers.
Normally the novel isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as good, when an author writes completely out of their &amp;ldquo;comfort zone&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treason by Don Brown</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2011/08/02/treason-by-don-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2011/08/02/treason-by-don-brown/</guid>
      <description>This used to be offered as a free book for the Kindle and was one of many I added to my account after receiving my Kindle. (If its free, its for me, right?)
When reading the author &amp;ldquo;Don Brown&amp;rdquo; on the cover of this novel, I was mistaking it for a more famous Dan Brown (Da Vinci Code). As I read the military themes unfold, my mind then played further tricks on me as I made a connection with Dale Brown&amp;rsquo;s military styled novels as the author.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H.M.S. Unseen by Patrick Robinson</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2008/12/14/hms-unseen-by-patrick-robinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2008/12/14/hms-unseen-by-patrick-robinson/</guid>
      <description>This is the second book by Patrick Robinson I could get my hands on. I really enjoyed reading Kilo Class and I enjoyed this book as well. It is set a couple years into the future, so Patrick gets to play with some technology that isn&amp;rsquo;t around quite yet.
The novel is an interesting story about a seriously skilled agent from Iraq. He infiltrated Israel&amp;rsquo;s navy and was trained as a submariner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kilo Class by Patrick Robinson</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2008/11/04/kilo-class-by-patrick-robinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2008/11/04/kilo-class-by-patrick-robinson/</guid>
      <description>This book was an accident. I needed a new book to read, because I was going to be waiting for something. The cover looked like a decent military technological drama. Since Tom Clancy cannot write books as fast as I can read them, I thought I would give it a try. It was a decent choice.
The premise is that Russia wants to sell Kilo class submarines to China. At $300 million a boat, it is much needed income for Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White-Out by James Vance Marshall</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/12/11/white-out-by-james-vance-marshall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/12/11/white-out-by-james-vance-marshall/</guid>
      <description>This is a book I happened on by chance. I picked it out of the new book section of the library by the title and checked it out after reading the inside cover. I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I did. While I only rate it 4 out of 5, it was an interesting book and worth reading.
The book is centered on telling the story of a Royal Navy officer and his trials to survive against impossible odds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deception Point by Dan Brown</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/06/02/deception-point-by-dan-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/06/02/deception-point-by-dan-brown/</guid>
      <description>The Da Vinci Code was the first book of Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s I read. It seemed like your only choice was to read the book, due to popularity. I really enjoy Brown&amp;rsquo;s style of writing, but didn&amp;rsquo;t like the far stretches required to make The Da Vinci Code a suspenseful novel and much of the false history. I guess it didn&amp;rsquo;t really bug me when reading the book. The thing that bugged me was people thinking it was the truth after reading a fictional novel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>