<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on joesacher.com</title>
    <link>http://joesacher.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on joesacher.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2002-2017 - Joe Sacher - All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://joesacher.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I Miss You, Dad</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2011/05/15/i-miss-you-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2011/05/15/i-miss-you-dad/</guid>
      <description>My father fought cancer for decades. He was the strongest man I have ever known. It was hard to see him wither with a body not able to do what his will desired. His suffering finally ended during the early morning of April 20th. Despite knowing that the cancer was terminal and preparing for it. Death is never easy. It tears a hole through you.
The storm was heavy. No matter what I did, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep the ship from going down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Chocolate Dipped Ginger Altoids</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/08/28/dark-chocolate-dipped-ginger-altoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/08/28/dark-chocolate-dipped-ginger-altoids/</guid>
      <description>Dark Chocolate Dipped Ginger Altoids. Yes, it sounds weird. I don’t understand how they made it through marketing. I don’t think they had any type of focus group for these. I have a rule that I will try anything once, as long as there isn’t a high likelihood of death. I think this is why blowfish is so expensive, for the malpractice insurance for those that die after eating it. I don’t plan on trying blowfish any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What an Engagement!</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/03/18/what-an-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/03/18/what-an-engagement/</guid>
      <description>Today I read of an engagement gone seriously wrong. Although, reading through the article I realized that had I been in that situation, things would have gone differently. Amy and I are a little different than the two in the article.
The incident started with a man concealing his $12,000 engagement ring in a helium balloon, with the idea of actually &amp;lsquo;popping&amp;rsquo; the question. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why he had not attached the balloon to something of a greater weight than the buoyancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday To Me</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/03/07/happy-birthday-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/03/07/happy-birthday-to-me/</guid>
      <description>Hurray for me. Today is my birthday.
Last night, I decided to make a German Chocolate Cake. Amy thought I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to make my own cake, but I wanted to try one from scratch. The cake used real melted chocolate and I folded in whipped egg whites. The frosting was pretty standard fare with egg yolks, evaporated milk, sugar, etc. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a piece until tonight. I cooked the cake a little too much and it was slightly dry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30,000 Hours Later...I&#39;m Engaged</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/02/26/30000-hours-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/02/26/30000-hours-later/</guid>
      <description>On September 24th, 2004, I met Amy for the first time on our date at Acapulco Joe’s in Downtown Indianapolis. Amy’s car broke down just before we met, so she was driving her dad’s old Ford Ranger. We have been seeing each other since. On Feb 26th, we were going to reach an obscure and geeky anniversary. We will have known each other for exactly 30,000 hours. About two months ago, I targeted this date for something I had been planning for almost a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Your Strengths</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/02/21/leveraging-your-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/02/21/leveraging-your-strengths/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately, I am easily bored.
My mind wandered during a meeting at work today as we were talking about leveraging your strengths. So I started drawing on my notepad.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2^1 / 2^2 / 2^3  2^4 : 2^5</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/02/04/power-of-two-date-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2008/02/04/power-of-two-date-time/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a geek, no doubt about it. Only a geek would notice that today is special. The date is 2^1&amp;frasl;2^2&amp;frasl;2^3 or 2/4/08. At 4:32 PM or 16:32, we have a time of 2^4:2^5. Sadly there are not 64 seconds.
Yes, and I AM aware that most places that describe dates in a sane way (like everywhere but the US), will have this day in April. :)  So enjoy a fun power of two date/time sequence that will not happen again for a hundred years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These things I wish</title>
      <link>http://joesacher.com/blog/2006/04/18/these-things-i-wish-for-each-of-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joesacher.com/blog/2006/04/18/these-things-i-wish-for-each-of-you/</guid>
      <description>This is something often attributed to Paul Harvey. While Paul often read material from this author, he was not the author. This was written by Lee Pitts in People Who Live at the End of Dirt Roads that appeared in the 2000 Chicken Soup for the Golden Soul.
For my grandchildren, I&amp;rsquo;d like better. I&amp;rsquo;d really like for them to know about hand-me-down clothes, homemade ice-cream and meat loaf sandwiches. I really would.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>