<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>joesacher.com</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.joesacher.com/</id><updated>2014-05-05T18:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Web Site Reboot</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/personal/web-site-reboot/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-05T18:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2014-05-05:blog/personal/web-site-reboot/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is hard for me to believe that I tried to go to a markdown or reStructured text driven web site over a year ago.
I started with a Ruby based solutions, thinking it would be a good time to learn.  But the only thing I really learned is that Ruby is a 2nd class citizen on Windows.
I need to do 60% of my work in Windows and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; can’t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times do you think I logged into my Linux &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; to update the site?  Other than the first time?  None.  Well, actually once.  I tried, but gems had been changed and I had dependency issues and…  I just let it sit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/en/3.3.0/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; first, because I am very comfortable with Python.  And Python is 80% as nice in Windows as Unix, maybe more.  People actually care if it doesn’t work in Windows.
So I came full circle and am now generating the site in Pelican and hosting on github pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style isn’t how I want it to end up, but back online.  It will grow with time, as I add new content and port over the old content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole process started with a outdated Wordpress install on a shared server, leading to compromised sites and blank sites.  One thing I’m sure of, it is better than Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="site related"></category></entry><entry><title>I Miss You, Dad</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/personal/i-miss-you-dad/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-05-15:blog/personal/i-miss-you-dad/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My father fought cancer for decades.  He was the strongest man I have ever known.  It was hard to see him wither with a body not able to do what his will desired.  His suffering finally ended during the early morning of April 20th.  Despite knowing that the cancer was terminal and preparing for it.  Death is never easy.  It tears a hole through you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storm was heavy.  No matter what I did, I couldn’t keep the ship from going down.  Long weekends driving down to be with Dad and doing anything I could to make him more comfortable, but the storm just grew.  The ship was groaning, in so much pain.  Then, faster than I could imagine, the ship is in splinters and I’m awash in the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m drowning with the ship’s wreckage all around me.  Trying to be strong and put on a brave face for the others floating with me, but the waves of grief come fast and are towering.  I gasp for breath and hope to survive.  There is a piece of wreckage that I grab.  A physical thing or two, a picture, memories of a certain time.  But all around me is wreckage reminding me of the beauty of the ship that was and now is gone.  For a while, all I can do is float. Survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The waves are shrinking.  I know they’ll be less frequent.  Some waves I’ll see coming for birthdays or while doing something we did together.  Some will surprise me, unexpectantly filling my mouth with water and making me gasp.  But I know I’ll get through them.  I know I’ll survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know that Dad is now reaping his reward, for years of service to the Lord.  That makes it easier to handle.  I never knew my dad’s dad and my namesake.  He died when my father was in his late teens.  It was up to dad to teach me of grandpa through himself and now I will have the task of teaching my unborn children of dad through me.  I hope I’m worthy of that task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one sure way to get dad to do something was to tell him it is impossible.  This is one of the best lessons dad taught me, that I could do anything.  I might have to learn something first and the worst that would happen is I would fail.  So what?  What happens most often is I didn’t.  In a world full of people scared to try, this was a great gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never realized how many lives dad touched.  With little notice, on a Thursday night, the largest funeral home in town was completely packed.  The line was out the door for hours.  Cars circled the lot to wait for someone to leave, just to have a spot.  A dozen times that night, someone came up to me and told me how much dad meant to them, with a story they had to tell.  So many things I never would have know he did.  Something dad probably just did from his nature and without a second thought.  Most would love to have touched that many lives when they are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss you, dad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I hope the waves never stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Bicycle Zen</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/personal/bicycle-zen/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-03-02:blog/personal/bicycle-zen/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Zen Teacher saw five of his students return from the market, riding their bicycles. When they had dismounted, the teacher asked the students, “Why are you riding your bicycles?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first student replied, “The bicycle is carrying this sack of potatoes. I am glad that I do not have to carry them on my back!” The teacher praised the student, saying, “You are a smart boy. When you grow old, you will not walk hunched over, as I do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second student replied, “I love to watch the trees and fields pass by as I roll down the path.” The teacher commended the student, “Your eyes are open and you see the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third student replied, “When I ride my bicycle, I am content to chant, nam myoho renge kyo.” The teacher gave praise to the third student, “Your mind will roll with the ease of a newly trued wheel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth student answered, “Riding my bicycle, I live in harmony with all beings.” The teacher was pleased and said, “You are riding on the golden path of non-harming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fifth student replied, “I ride my bicycle to ride my bicycle.” The teacher went and sat at the feet of the fifth student, and said, “I am your disciple.”&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="thoughts"></category><category term="bicycle"></category></entry><entry><title>Dark Chocolate Dipped Ginger Altoids</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/personal/dark-chocolate-dipped-ginger-altoids/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-08-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2008-08-28:blog/personal/dark-chocolate-dipped-ginger-altoids/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 234px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/singles/ginger-altoids.jpg" style="width: 234px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Warning: An Experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark Chocolate Dipped Ginger Altoids. Yes, it sounds weird. I don’t understand how they made it through marketing. I don’t think they had any type of focus group for these. I have a rule that I will try anything once, as long as there isn’t a high likelihood of death. I think this is why blowfish is so expensive, for the malpractice insurance for those that die after eating it. I don’t plan on trying blowfish any time soon. But I’m game for Dark Chocolate Dipped Ginger Altoids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me see if I can take you through it. You pop this mint in your mouth pretty quick. See this isn’t an M&amp;amp;M. it will melt in your hand. So you have to pop it in quick.  And if you wait too long, you might just lose your nerve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first flavor that you get is dark chocolate. Some people like dark chocolate, but I prefer milk chocolate. So I’m dealing with the chocolate when the other flavors start. Imagine that your are eating the most over-spiced pumpkin pie that you have ever tasted… but it is covered in dark chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was mildly strange. After some time, the chocolate has been sucked off and you are just sucking on a piece of pumpkin pie. Well sort of. But you have been desensitized to the spice, so it seems a little like pumpkin pie. But something is hiding there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heat starts to pour in. It makes sense. I had forgotten that these were Altoids. And they are curiously strong. I should have expected this. So the heat is building and I feel like I am eating a super hot radish. That is covered in ginger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, after you have had an Altoids, your breath is usually fresh. It has to be, because you have burned off a the top four layers of skin in your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is different. My breath smells worse. It is actually making me gag. A breath mint shouldn’t make your breath worse. My breath is like I left a pumkin pie in a hot car all day. A really old car. With a gym bag. Really bad breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it should have been a clue when Julie put out the Altoids tin. She said that she tried a few and wasn’t sure about how they taste. They are now available for others to sample. I should have seen something there, because you protect the Altoids. You make sure that no one is around and sneak one out quick and then hide it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all of this, if you are offered a Dark Chocolate Dipped Ginger Altoids, try one. It is an experience. Maybe not a good one, but good lives are chains of experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But please get a real mint before you come around me to breathe all your pumpkin pie breath on me.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="humor"></category></entry><entry><title>30,000 Hours Later…I’m Engaged.</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/personal/30000-hours-later/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-26T19:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2008-02-26:blog/personal/30000-hours-later/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 300px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/singles/30000-hours-later.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The ring on her finger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 24th, 2004, I met Amy for the first time on our date at Acapulco Joe’s in Downtown Indianapolis. Amy’s car broke down just before we met, so she was driving her dad’s old Ford Ranger. We have been seeing each other since. On Feb 26th, we were going to reach an obscure and geeky anniversary. We will have known each other for exactly 30,000 hours. About two months ago, I targeted this date for something I had been planning for almost a year. She said, “Yes.” I’m now engaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last few months, I’ve been very careful with how I didn’t give away surprises, while knowing I was giving them away. I knew I would need Amy to know my “tell”. The latest was my response to her asking if I had her favorite pizza place make a heart shaped pizza for Valentine’s Day. This was after I told her a food place was going to make dinner in a way they didn’t think about till I asked if they could. I kind of looked away and gave her a “no comment”, when she asked if I was having a pizza made in a heart. When the heart shaped pizza showed up, she already knew it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I told Amy to reserve February 26th as a date night, she didn’t think anything of it. She didn’t know of any special date or anniversary for the 26th. Amy immediately tried to figure out what we were doing, but I gave no clues. After many days, she came across the idea of going out for a play or a movie. Here my months of “giving away” my secret plans had come into play. I “gave away” that I had no comment about that. Amy bought it hook, line and sinker. Now, I just had many things to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important piece was getting insurance for and picking up the ring. Without that, nothing happens. Since I work at an insurance company, I consulted some co-workers for best ideas about getting coverage for this ring. It wasn’t a cheap ring and would really hurt to lose it, damage it, have it stolen, etc. With all of those details taken care of, I picked up the ring in early February. I had to bring it to work on the day I picked it up, because of the way the timing worked out. I told the co-worker who helped with insurance advice that I had picked it up. She asked to see it. I said, “No. Men have died for less than showing someone an engagement before she gets it.” After thinking about it, she agreed. When I got home, I had to find a good hiding place. Just knowing that the ring was sitting there and I couldn’t say anything was tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started preparations and tried to keep them secret. I was on a time crunch for making the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; and would up letting Amy know about it, just playing it off as a fun scavenger hunt to start the date. I didn’t finish it until the night before the “date.” It was really dorky, but I thought she would get a kick out if it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole night was almost blown as we left work, a day before the big event. A co-worker who knew about my plans yelled, “Good Luck Joe!” I reacted with a quieter, “Its not tonight.” Then I shut up and hoped Amy didn’t hear anything. I learned later that she did, just didn’t think it was for anything special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the day was here and I gave Amy a note at 5:20, then left in her truck. It isn’t running very well and took some will power to get to the destination. She now drives a Passat and I use the truck when we need to haul things a short distance. The front of the note indicated that it shouldn’t be opened till 5:30. Then the note told Amy to get in my car (which I left in the driveway) and start it at exactly 5:40. By that time, I was almost to the restaurant. The parking spot I was looking for and hoping to be empty was empty. It is an important spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Amy Cox, this is your mission should you chose to accept it.” That audio greeted Amy as she started the car. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; consisted of me being a dork and Mission Impossible music, with directions. At a few places where the timing was unknown, I had her skip to the next track once she reached various places. I figured that she would know where she was heading about half way there. It didn’t really matter if she found out. I had more planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had thought about standing outside, right were I was waiting for her on our first date. I decided not to for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She would wonder why and possibly think it was a really special day (we couldn’t have that)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was &lt;span class="caps"&gt;REALLY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;COLD&lt;/span&gt;. I was willing to do it if I had not thought of #1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy arrived a little after 6 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;. I was sitting in the same booth we sat on our first date. This wasn’t an accident. I had come previously and made sure to have it reserved. However, I had done this once before on the anniversary of our first date, so nothing to shockingly new yet. After all, this was the 26th, not the 24th, and February, not September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner was nice. We chatted and Amy couldn’t figure out something special was going on. All according to plan. After dinner we ordered dessert. We had never eaten dessert at Acapulco Joe’s. Cheesecake was odd for a Mexican Restaurant, but the fried ice-cream felt at home. Amy took the cherry, but gave me the stem. I like seeing how fast I can tie them into a knot with my tongue. When we left the table, I slipped the tied stem into my pocket for something cheesy later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During dinner, Amy asked what I had to haul in the truck, because that was the reason I told her I was taking it. I wouldn’t tell. She worried that it was sitting in the back of the truck to be stolen. I told her that it fit in the cab. This made her ask why I didn’t just take the car. To that I said nothing and changed the subject. I couldn’t tell her that the cargo I was carrying in the truck was the most expensive thing that truck has ever carried. It wasn’t sitting in the truck, it was in my coat pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left at 6:54 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;. I told Amy that the rest of the night required the truck and we walked towards it. While crossing the street Amy mentioned, “Its funny. I drove the truck here on our first date and you drove the Maxima.” I resisted the urge to reply quickly and acted out my best thinking look for 10 seconds. Then I replied, “I guess so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked up the sidewalk towards the truck. When she spotted it, she said “That is about were I parked, too.” It was actually exactly where she parked. The last spot before the hydrant. “Really?” was all I said. I told her she needed to get in the truck, but she couldn’t find her keys in her purse. I opened the door for her. As she started to get in the truck I told her to turn around. I got down on one knee and said some of the things that I had written down throughout the week. I was nervous and don’t remember exactly what I said. The only part that I can really remember is that it was exactly 30,000 hours since we first met and I’ve loved spending a majority of those hours since then with her. I should have had the camera ready to capture her face when she realized what was going on. I placed the ring on her finger and she just stared at it. I let her enjoy it for a while before reaching in my pocket to get something to put in the box. Then I gave her the closed box and told her that wasn’t all. She opened the box and I said, “Here is the knot I tied on the night I asked you to tie the knot.” Cheezy, but she laughed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that she thought we were going to see a movie or play tonight, so I gave her the option of going to see a movie. She said that she didn’t know, but that sounded good. As we were walking to the truck, Amy had mentioned how cold it was. I offered to drive her back to the car in the truck. She mentioned that she didn’t feel cold any more. I just walked her back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were to meet up just south of 465, then get in the car for the rest of the way. When I almost got there, my cell phone rang. It was Amy. She called her mom on the way home and was on auto pilot. She was almost home, instead of heading to where we were supposed to meet. I’m guessing shock was involved. She told me that she probably couldn’t stay still for a movie and wanted to tell everyone. I thought that would be the case, but she told me she wanted to go. I started driving back to her house. Amy spent the rest of the night and all day at work showing everyone her ring. I was glad that I was finally out of the “When you giving her a ring?” question. I didn’t know that it was immediately replaced with another question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You two set a date yet?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Not yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: We were married on June 6th, 2009&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="proposal"></category><category term="marriage"></category></entry><entry><title>Leveraging Your Strengths</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/personal/leveraging-your-strengths/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2008-02-21:blog/personal/leveraging-your-strengths/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I am easily bored.  My mind wandered during a meeting at work today as we were talking about leveraging your strengths.  So I started drawing on my notepad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.joesacher.com/images/posts/singles/leverage-strengths.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
</summary><category term="humor"></category></entry><entry><title>2^1 / 2^2 / 2^3 2^4 : 2^5</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/personal/power-of-two-date-time/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2008-02-04:blog/personal/power-of-two-date-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a geek, no doubt about it.  Only a geek would notice that today is special.  The date is 2^1/2^2/2^3 or 2/4/08.  At 4:32 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt; or 16:32, we have a time of 2^4:2^5.  Sadly there are not 64 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Yes, and I &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; aware that most places that describe dates in a sane way (like everywhere but the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;), will have this day in April.  :)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So enjoy a fun power of two date/time sequence that will not happen again for a hundred years.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="humor"></category></entry></feed>