<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>joesacher.com - reviews</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/feeds/reviews.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.joesacher.com/</id><updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Playing for Pizza by John Grisham</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/playing-for-pizza-by-john-grisham/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-08-02:/blog/reviews/playing-for-pizza-by-john-grisham/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/playing-for-pizza.jpg" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I was intrigued when I read the summary of this book.  A novel by John Grisham about a third string &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; quarterback, escaping his terrible past to play professional football in Italy.  Nothing about lawyers?  This sounds interesting, if not just to figure out why John described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally the novel isn’t quite as good, when an author writes completely out of their “comfort zone”.  That is definitely the case here.  It doesn’t have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/playing-for-pizza.jpg" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I was intrigued when I read the summary of this book.  A novel by John Grisham about a third string &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; quarterback, escaping his terrible past to play professional football in Italy.  Nothing about lawyers?  This sounds interesting, if not just to figure out why John described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally the novel isn’t quite as good, when an author writes completely out of their “comfort zone”.  That is definitely the case here.  It doesn’t have the same fire as a typical Grisham thriller.  That isn’t to say it is a bad book.  I enjoyed the read and it was fun to see a different side of this author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts with Rick Dockery in a hospital bed, after the worst game of his varied &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; career.  In the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFC&lt;/span&gt; Championship game, this third string player is forced into the game with 11 minutes left.  The Browns are up 20-0.  Rick manages to toss enough interceptions to loose the game and Cleveland’s Super Bowl ticket.  The last hit of the game mercifully knocks him senseless and offers a day with no memory of what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All bridges burned, Rick’s only available job is playing for the Parma Panthers in Italy, where American Football ranks at near the bottom of all sports.  Games are free, yet less than a couple hundred attend.  Only three Americans are allowed per team and they are the only players paid any money.  It seemed like the same as a Softball league in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;, a proud hobby to most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The description of the four hour Italian meals made me want to go to Italy, just for the food.  It was obvious that Grisham had spent some time in Italy and really wanted to give the read an appreciation of the country.  I wish his character development was as endearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rick is a typical womanizing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; player at the start of the novel.  He doesn’t seem to change.  Some of the characters are fleshed out well, but most are flat.  It is a story about an American &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; player in Italy.  That is it.  The plot could have used much more development and choices for story direction at times were just boring.  The romance near the end of the book is empty.  I felt that Rick and his girlfriend were together because it was convenient.  I had hoped for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book would have been harder to get published, if written by a non-famous author.    If you are not a fan of football, you will probably not enjoy this novel.  Most of the conflicts and growth occur only in relation to football.  Rick doesn’t grow much as a person, otherwise.  It is worth reading and is a short and quick book.  I think the library is a great place to get a copy, because you probably won’t want to read it again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>Treason by Don Brown</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/treason-by-don-brown/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-08-02:/blog/reviews/treason-by-don-brown/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 170px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/Treason-DonBrown.png" style="width: 170px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This used to be offered as a free book for the Kindle and was one of many I added to my account after receiving my Kindle. (If its free, its for me, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reading the author “Don Brown” on the cover of this novel, I was mistaking it for a more famous Dan Brown (Da Vinci Code). As I read the military themes unfold, my mind then played further tricks on me as I made a connection with Dale …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 170px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/Treason-DonBrown.png" style="width: 170px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This used to be offered as a free book for the Kindle and was one of many I added to my account after receiving my Kindle. (If its free, its for me, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reading the author “Don Brown” on the cover of this novel, I was mistaking it for a more famous Dan Brown (Da Vinci Code). As I read the military themes unfold, my mind then played further tricks on me as I made a connection with Dale Brown’s military styled novels as the author.  None of this is important in discussing the merits and faults of this novel, which shares more with John Grisham than either of the other two authors mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Treason&lt;/em&gt; is the first book in Don Brown’s Navy Justice series, which follows Navy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; (Judge Advocate General) Lieutenant Zack Brewer through two major cases.  This feels familiar to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; series. Don Brown is a former &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; Officer and thus the similarities between the two are actually similarities between both and the actual Military Justice System of the United States.  All interactions and procedures portrayed in the book seem real and believable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an average novel, but not a great one. I was confused by the level of discussion of faith throughout the book, tempered mostly by my assumption that the author was one of those discussed above. It was surprising that they would break form and include some discussion of Christian faith and beliefs, when not directly germane to the plot. As a Christian, I actually enjoyed what it added to the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the novel, I realized that the publisher is Zondervan, one of the largest Bible and Evangelical Christian book publishers.  Thus the inclusion of Christian themes is less surprising.  I actually found it much more subtle than other novels with tangential Christian teaching which I have read in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard not to compare this book to works from John Grisham, who is after all a master of the courtroom novel. Unfortunately, Don Brown does not quite make the cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel opens with Muslim leaders discussing the infiltration of sleeper agents into the United States Armed Forces.  As the story unfolds, we learn that a lawsuit was won which allowed Muslim Chaplains into the Armed Forces. Some of these Chaplains are handlers to infiltrate and create a network of like minded Muslim soldiers to attack the enemy from within.  This is truly a scary premise and one which is an undeniably fertile ground for a great story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muslim soldiers are committing acts of terror.  One instance, a soldier brings grenades to a Christian church where a discussion of Islam was occurring.  The bomber demands that the preacher admit that Mohammed is the one true prophet and explodes two grenades when the preacher stands his ground.  Many are killed, along with the attacker. In a second instance, a sniper assassinates the Ambassador from Israel, before committing suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first trial in the book is mostly for setting the ball rolling and introducing the main players.  A Navy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SEAL&lt;/span&gt; is accused of raping an officer, who is the niece of a prominent Senator.  I found it amusing that the novel included a token “Reverend” whose only preaching occurs by talking about oppressed minorities to the press. This just rings a little too true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zach is prosecuting the case against a beautiful &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; officer, who hates Zach due to a previous encounter.  Throughout the trial, the truth is unknown. The rape accusation sounds fishy and Zach is troubled by his thought that he might not be doing the correct thing in putting the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SEAL&lt;/span&gt; away. Unfortunately, this theme is almost immediately dropped at the conclusion of the first trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a F-18 Hornet is destroyed by another jihadist, who plants explosives in the fighter. This is the event which starts the investigation of the main case in the novel.  The United States vs the 3 Chaplains who ran the jihadists in the military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we have cross plots of possible future political aspirations of the young Lieutenant Zack with a possible pairing with the famous Senator’s niece.  The problem is the main meat and potatoes of the novel is the second trial.  This is where the novel falters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President of the United States allows cameras into the courtroom for the first time in a Court Marshal. I initially wondered why and realized later that it was for the benefit of the writer. Far too often, when major portions of the case were to happen, the plot was moved forward by tangential characters hearing the summary on the evening news.  It seems as though the author assumed all readers would skim this part anyway, so he did the skimming for them.  The drama is in the courtroom: what is said, what is done.  The novel is lesser for leaving much of this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it is a novel I enjoyed reading, but wouldn’t read again. The plot was predictable and linear. Characters one dimensional with little ambiguity. Everything is very black and white. I assumed the ending in the first few chapters and unfortunately was absolutely correct.  Surprises were few and far between.  I my eventually read the other two books in this series, but I’m in not rush to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>H.M.S. Unseen by Patrick Robinson</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/hms-unseen-by-patrick-robinson/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-12-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2008-12-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2008-12-14:/blog/reviews/hms-unseen-by-patrick-robinson/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 138px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/hms-unseen.jpg" style="width: 138px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second book by Patrick Robinson I could get my hands on.  I really enjoyed reading &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/kilo-class-by-patrick-robinson/"&gt;Kilo Class&lt;/a&gt; and I enjoyed this book as well.  It is set a couple years into the future, so Patrick gets to play with some technology that isn’t around quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel is an interesting story about a seriously skilled agent from Iraq.  He infiltrated Israel’s navy and was trained as a submariner.  His employer decides that he is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 138px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/hms-unseen.jpg" style="width: 138px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second book by Patrick Robinson I could get my hands on.  I really enjoyed reading &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/kilo-class-by-patrick-robinson/"&gt;Kilo Class&lt;/a&gt; and I enjoyed this book as well.  It is set a couple years into the future, so Patrick gets to play with some technology that isn’t around quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel is an interesting story about a seriously skilled agent from Iraq.  He infiltrated Israel’s navy and was trained as a submariner.  His employer decides that he is too large of a risk and attempts to eliminate him.  After walking across the desert to escape Iraq, he makes a deal with Iran to help commit acts of terrorism using his submarine skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A satisfying book to a Clancy fan.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>Kilo Class by Patrick Robinson</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/kilo-class-by-patrick-robinson/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2008-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2008-11-04:/blog/reviews/kilo-class-by-patrick-robinson/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/kilo-class.jpg" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an accident.  I needed a new book to read, because I was going to be waiting for something.  The cover looked like a decent military technological drama.  Since Tom Clancy cannot write books as fast as I can read them, I thought I would give it a try.  It was a decent choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise is that Russia wants to sell Kilo class submarines to China.  At $300 million a boat, it is much needed income for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/kilo-class.jpg" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an accident.  I needed a new book to read, because I was going to be waiting for something.  The cover looked like a decent military technological drama.  Since Tom Clancy cannot write books as fast as I can read them, I thought I would give it a try.  It was a decent choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise is that Russia wants to sell Kilo class submarines to China.  At $300 million a boat, it is much needed income for Russia.  However, if China does get a fleet of Kilos, they can shut the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; out of the region with this quite electric/diesel boat and possibly eventually retake Taiwan.  The book contains some interesting black ops submarine work, some ground based special ops action and a cool under ice crossing of the north pole that I didn’t know was possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I you like Clancy, you will enjoy this book.  If you don’t like Clancy, what is wrong with you?  (Just Kidding.)  It wasn’t a great book, but a good read.   Also see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/hms-unseen-by-patrick-robinson/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;H.M.&lt;/span&gt;S Unseen&lt;/a&gt; by the same author.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>On Writing by Stephen King</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/on-writing-by-stephen-king/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2008-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2008-07-03:/blog/reviews/on-writing-by-stephen-king/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/on-writing.jpg" style="width: 151px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve started writing again.  In the last few years, all my writing was on screenplay style for short films.  Some of these we actually shot and produced, most just sit on my computer in final &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; form.  Writing in screenplay format is different than novel, novella, or short story forms.  Screenplay is all about dialog and character actions.  There is no exposition of character thoughts.  I think this experience makes you a stronger dialog writer, when you switch to fiction.  I decided to read a few books on the subject of writing fiction before starting up again. Seeing good reviews on Stephen King’s &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;On Writing&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;, I decided to read it.  I’m glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 151px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/on-writing.jpg" style="width: 151px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve started writing again.  In the last few years, all my writing was on screenplay style for short films.  Some of these we actually shot and produced, most just sit on my computer in final &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; form.  Writing in screenplay format is different than novel, novella, or short story forms.  Screenplay is all about dialog and character actions.  There is no exposition of character thoughts.  I think this experience makes you a stronger dialog writer, when you switch to fiction.  I decided to read a few books on the subject of writing fiction before starting up again. Seeing good reviews on Stephen King’s &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;On Writing&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;, I decided to read it.  I’m glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is broken into a few sections: C.V., Toolbox, On Writing, On Living: A Postscript, and a final edit example.  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;C.V.&lt;/span&gt; or Curriculum Vitae is normally a list of job experience and education for use in an interview.  At first, this seemed like a strange title for the section.  After I finished reading, it was a logical name.  The section is split into 38 mini-chapters or “snapshots” of times in history, as Stephen puts it.  Descriptions of points in his life, which influenced his focus and style as a writer, help give perspective on all the rest of the book.  King is very open with his battles with drugs and alcohol over the years.   He laments about those books written while under the influence, with no lasting memory of the creative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toolbox describes all those tools that you need in your collection as a writer.  It isn’t a boring grammatical lessons, but covers those differences between what your English teacher tells you is correct grammar and how a novelist should actually write.  One subject that King admits is more of a do what I say, rather than do what I do, is limiting adverbs.  “I have a problem with this,” Joe said admittedly.  Screenplay writing is actually a negative in the regard, especially when you are directing or at least participating on the crew side of something you write.  I tend to see it in my head the production of the piece and write more stage direction than I should.   This is even easier to do if the location is known while you are writing.  These stage directions are the adverbs of a screenplay.  Stephen states that this is just a sign that your writing isn’t strong enough for the reader to understand how a character would do something.  There are many other worthwhile tips and some just opinions.  But they are good opinions.  I enjoyed the idea of writing as telekinesis.  Your mind is controlling this little cast of characters.  Just write down what they do.  A very interesting perspective on the art of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Writing deals with using those tools and good habits to create a work.  It is interesting to learn processes from different prospectives.  Some use plot visualization or something like the snowflakes method, to complete the entire plot before they start writing.  While this outline isn’t binding as to the direction the writing must take, I’m sure it has some limiting pull, if only subconsciously.  King admits to having plotted once and hated it.  He now just writes and lets the story take him where it will.  The two styles yield different books.  I have no doubt that a technical thriller, such as Tom Clancy, is well plotted and definitely well researched.  The book is about the story.  King’s books are more about the characters first, and story second.  Perhaps that is the difference between the two methods.  As King puts it, he just gets characters in a predicament and watches as they work themselves free.  His plot for most books start with a simple What if? question.  Taking two ideas and putting them together for a unique situation.  I thought the idea of a book as a fossil was interesting.  You can slowly brush away the dirt and find all the pieces unbroken, or use the plotted jackhammer to see what the fossils are faster, possibly breaking some.  Interesting comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Living is a section about being hit by the van and nearly killed.  I have not followed Stephen King very much at all, so the most I knew before this book was that he had an accident.   I did not realize how close to dying he actually came.  This is an appropriate book to hold this information, as the composition of &lt;em&gt;On Writing&lt;/em&gt; bookended the accident.  He had gained momentum on finishing the book, after a sizable delay, when the accident occurred.  This was the book he worked on as he allowed writing to bring him back into life again.  The very last information in the book is valuable as King shows the reader an original, first draft section of 1408.  Then gives an corrected version, showing markup and giving references to why changes were done.  A very good lesson in revision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I have not read many Stephen King books, this was a worthwhile read.  It would be enjoyable for those who are not writers, but just want to become better readers.  I’ve found the same thing with films, after becoming a filmmaker.  Fully understanding that art can allow you to enjoy it better, if it is good.  It also allows you to notice when it is done poorly.  My girlfriend is slightly annoyed when I dissect poor film making choices while watching a movie.   Luckily, dissecting poor writing will only be done quietly inside my head.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="nonfiction"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>Jet Mini vs PSI Turncrafter Pro</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/a-lathe-comparison-jet-mini-vs-psi-turncrafter-pro/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2007-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-26:/blog/reviews/a-lathe-comparison-jet-mini-vs-psi-turncrafter-pro/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was looking at lathes, I talked with many people who had tried and liked either the Jet Mini or the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; Turncrafter Pro lathes. I could not find many that had used both, to get an idea of the differences between them. Now owning a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; Turncrafter Pro and having taken a class and used a Jet Mini for 5 hours or so, I decided to summarize the differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both lathes look deceptively similar. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; is 4 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was looking at lathes, I talked with many people who had tried and liked either the Jet Mini or the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; Turncrafter Pro lathes. I could not find many that had used both, to get an idea of the differences between them. Now owning a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; Turncrafter Pro and having taken a class and used a Jet Mini for 5 hours or so, I decided to summarize the differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both lathes look deceptively similar. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; is 4” longer in the bed at 18”, vs 14” for the Jet. The Jet also has one higher speed. The first 5 speed ranges seem to be very close. The beds look almost exactly the same, as do the banjo and steady rest. The motor height adjustment is almost exactly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality wise, the Jet has a nicer finish and features. By this, I mean the machining is a little better cleaned up and parts are more thought out. The threads on my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; headstock looked like there were cut and never touched again. There are burrs and sharp edges that I will be dressing down. While the Jet lathe I was using had been in use at the classroom for a while, I haven”t noticed this on Jet minis out on display at shops either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major difference, which will affect daily use, are the belt access doors. The Jet has a nice flip open door for both top and bottom access. Although the spring handle setup for the bottom door seems a little strange to me, it works fast once you get used to it. The access to the belts are in exactly the same spot, but the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; has a thumb screw to undo and then a little plastic piece which is lifted and removed. This piece has slits on the bottom that sits on bolts screwed in below the opening. The piece would be set down for the change then replaced. It makes for a piece to lose and takes over twice as long to change the belt speed as on the Jet. I will be replacing my plastic pieces with doors that have a spring clip, similar to the Jet’s. Currently my access panels are off, because they are annoying to remove and replace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The locking handle on the steady rest and the tail stock depth lock are both a plastic handles on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt;. The operation is the same, both spring loaded handles which can be lifted to change position. The plastic handles don’t feel flimsy, but I doubt they will last quite as long as the metal handles on the Jet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point to point, my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; is slightly off (1/32” tail is closer to me than the head point).  While a thin shim under the tail will fix this, I”m not sure if this is typical with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; or not. My sample size is 1. I did not see this with the 4 Jet lathes I looked at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still happy with my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; purchase. After I spend a little bit of time to polish off some of the rough edges and I will have a nice lathe for about $100 less than the Jet. I don’t see the loss of the high end (3800 rpm or so) on the Jet as too much of a problem. 3200 rpm is fast enough and both have the 500 rpm low end. But there is no doubt, the Jet is a better finished machine, with a few upgrades over the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt;. If I could have found the Jet on special for within $20-40 of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt;, I would have paid the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="woodworking"></category><category term="lathes"></category></entry><entry><title>I am Legend</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/review-i-am-legend/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2007-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-26:/blog/reviews/review-i-am-legend/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The best thing I can say for the new I am Legend movie is that it made me aware of Richard Matheson’s 1954 novel of the same name.  I decided to give it a read before the movie came out.  If you haven’t read it yet and plan to see the movie, don’t read it until after the movie.  It will ruin the movie for you.  Not in how much it gives away of the movie, but …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The best thing I can say for the new I am Legend movie is that it made me aware of Richard Matheson’s 1954 novel of the same name.  I decided to give it a read before the movie came out.  If you haven’t read it yet and plan to see the movie, don’t read it until after the movie.  It will ruin the movie for you.  Not in how much it gives away of the movie, but in how much the movie doesn’t give you anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers will follow for both the book and movie.  If you are interested in either, just bookmark this and come back after you have read/seen one or both.  You are warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been a big fan of the horror genre, because they just always seem silly to me.  I am Legend is in some parts silly as well.  It is a decent popcorn movie, but not much more.  The times where I wished it would follow some of the inspired twists in the book, but I was disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Legend opens with newscast audio playing over the traditional logos.  Video cuts to some doctor, played by Emma Thompson, discussing a new method of battling cancer: a mutating virus.  It is odd that she isn’t happier about discussing this discovery.  You wonder if the director was trying to foreshadow or just let the viewer guess that the doctor knows there are problems with her magic solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then cut to 3 years later with overgrown vegetation filled New York City and Will Smith’s character tearing down streets in a Mustang.  Here the movie starts straying from the book and from believability.  Robert Neville of the book realized that he was on his own.  If he got hurt, he would die.  Robert Neville of the movie (Will Smith) seems happy speeding through town, dodging parked cars, armored personnel carriers, and other cement and steel objects to hunt deer at 50 mph.  I don’t see that happening in a place where if you crash a car badly, you die.  There are no paramedics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting part of the book was the growth of Neville as he learned to survive and learned about the infected.  He traveled to the library to learn about bacteria and microscopes and how to investigate the situation.  The “monsters” were two types of vampires: the infected living and the dead reanimated.  The dead were more like traditional zombies and the living were intelligent and capable of learning.  They did not possess super human strength and were feared because of their numbers, not power and intelligence.  Neville’s location was not a secret and they haunted and taunted him outside his home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the movie involves Neville living in a classy, well decorated home.  He has generators under the counter. (I guess he pumps the exhaust outside.)  With a future where electricity is hard to come by, Neville does his research in the basement, using technical toys that would be annoying even in modern day.  He video logs his research with a lipstick camera eyeglasses, just to record pass and fail on test subjects.  All recorded to 6 backup hard drives.  Seriously, how hard is paper and pen?  It isn’t like hard drives are good backups when they are all stacked on top of each other to be destroyed in a fire.  Run a low power copier and distribute the paper copies a few places.  I guess that wouldn’t be visual and flashy.  it would just be a smart use of limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monsters in the movie are super-human terrors.  Once they find out where Neville lives, his steel shuttered residence with stadium lights and perimeter explosives, is no match for the creatures who just tear through thick plastered walls and ceilings.  The make up effects and probably tons of computer effects made the infected into scary, bestial creatures.  What made them interesting in the book was their human qualities.  I was glad that this wasn’t a gore fest, but it might as well have been.  Any qualities that existed in the book that made it more intelligent than a standard horror fare were almost gone in the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there have been other adaptations of the book, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0058700/"&gt;The Last Man on Earth (1964)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0067525/"&gt;The Omega Man (1971)&lt;/a&gt;, none have come close to capturing the book.  Matheson was involved with Last Man on Earth, until the script was changed and he asked for his name to be removed from the film.  I guess I have a naive belief that if a movie takes a books title, it should bear some semblance to the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This movie is saved somewhat with the fine acting of Smith, but is nothing more than a popcorn action flick.  The cinematography showed some beautiful vistas of post apocalyptic New York, but lacked inspiration at times.  One high point in visuals involved infected dogs wanting to attack Neville, held at bay by a slowly shrinking line of sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Neville of the film is a much more interesting person &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BEFORE&lt;/span&gt; the virus hits, but not near so much after.  In fact, it falls into the movie cliché of one of the few people that can fix the problem being on of the ones that is left to fix it.  He is obviously important, being a possibly savior from the virus and on the cover of Time magazine.  If it is explained how one of possible 10,000 in the world that could find the cure, is somehow immune to the virus, I missed it.  In contrast, Neville of the book is the average man that just happens to be immune.  Any knowledge he has to learn for beating the virus (or bacteria in the book) is hard won.  He is a person with many faults.  He drinks too much.  He isn’t nice.  Not a Hollywood hero.  He is real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem I have with the film adaptation is the perversion of the title: I am Legend.  It has lost the sad irony of the book.  Neville is not a legend among the infected, to be dealt with.  He becomes a legend among the survivors.  In the book, Neville determines the bacterium that causes the infection.  He doesn’t realize that the living infected have created a drug which allows them to deal with the effects.  They have formed society.  Neville has become a legend by killing the infected when they rest, during the day.   He is feared as the last old style human.  He is captured by the new society and sentenced to death.  The kicker is that he is infiltrated by an infected agent, an infected woman acting as a human.  This is what made seeing the woman and boy in the film, with no twist, so frustrating.  In the film, Neville finds a cure and proceeds to die in heroic Hollywood fashion, passing the cure on to save the few humans left.  Hurrah, hope for survivors.  It seems that irony is not a good enough ending.  Everyone must be happy when they leave the theater, even if the ending stinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reading books about writing fiction, I was recently exposed to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deus_ex_machina"&gt;deus ex machina&lt;/a&gt;, a latin phrase meaning literally “god out of a machine.”  It is often used to describe when the resolution of the story just happens without proper setup or reason.  It is talked about often, because the audience needs to believe in the motivation of the characters to not lose their suspension of disbelief.  The ending to the film is just a very bad example of deus ex machina.  It helps make a mediocre movie only more so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Legend has enough special effects to do well at the box office, but why does film have to be dumbed down this much for people to consume it?  I might have to read the book again to get this bad taste out of my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="movie"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Bicycling Coast to Coast by Donna Ikenberry</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/bicycling-coast-to-coast/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2007-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-15:/blog/reviews/bicycling-coast-to-coast/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/bicycling-coast-to-coast.jpg" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I realized that my recumbent would allow me to complete my dream of riding a bicycle across the country, I started research all over the web.  While reading through the many trip reports of coast to coast touring cyclists, two things became clear.  First, I would be riding the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org/routes/transamerica.cfm"&gt;TransAmerica trail&lt;/a&gt; created by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org"&gt;Adventure Cycling&lt;/a&gt; in 1976 (the year of my birth).  Second, I should purchase, read, re-read, and take along Donna’s book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/bicycling-coast-to-coast.jpg" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I realized that my recumbent would allow me to complete my dream of riding a bicycle across the country, I started research all over the web.  While reading through the many trip reports of coast to coast touring cyclists, two things became clear.  First, I would be riding the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org/routes/transamerica.cfm"&gt;TransAmerica trail&lt;/a&gt; created by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org"&gt;Adventure Cycling&lt;/a&gt; in 1976 (the year of my birth).  Second, I should purchase, read, re-read, and take along Donna’s book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read through Donna’s book at least once.  It is divided into 82 days worth of riding to cross the country, so I often will read a few of the day accounts at a time.  Normally I read sections to compare and contrast them with other on-line travelogues, jotting notes in the book.  Each day has a literary description of the ride, followed with turn by turn directions and points of interest.  This book was published in 1996, so you should not take it as gospel that “Joe Blowe’s Convienient Mart” will still be there.  As an adventure cyclist, you wouldn’t always want to know, would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book can get you across the country without a problem, however, you should use it along with the excellent &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org/routes/"&gt;maps&lt;/a&gt; provided by Adventure Cycling.  These maps are a cyclist dream, without all of the pitfalls contained in standard road maps.  Do you wonder which of the nearest towns have a bike shop, or a post office, or a laundry mat?  It’s on the map.  The many Adventure Cycling trips across the country every year keep the maps as up to date as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m left in May of 2002, with this book in my bag, to spend &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.joesacher.com/category/trans-am.html"&gt;4 months riding across this great country of ours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When are you leaving?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0898864682?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;tag=joesacher-20&amp;amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;amp;creativeASIN=0898864682"&gt;Bicycling Coast to Coast: A Complete Route Guide Virginia to Oregon  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;: 0898864682 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="nonfiction"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>White-Out by James Vance Marshall</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/white-out-by-james-vance-marshall/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2007-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-11:/blog/reviews/white-out-by-james-vance-marshall/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/white-out.jpg" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book I happened on by chance.  I picked it out of the new book section of the library by the title and checked it out after reading the inside cover.  I’m glad that I did.  While I only rate it 4 out of 5, it was an interesting book and worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is centered on telling the story of a Royal Navy officer and his trials to survive against impossible odds.  The main story …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/white-out.jpg" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book I happened on by chance.  I picked it out of the new book section of the library by the title and checked it out after reading the inside cover.  I’m glad that I did.  While I only rate it 4 out of 5, it was an interesting book and worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is centered on telling the story of a Royal Navy officer and his trials to survive against impossible odds.  The main story is set during the Second World War on the continent of Antarctica.  The British Royal Navy sends a small force to establish a weather station while also carrying out a top-secret mission.  A German U-Boat intercepts the periodic weather forecasts and is able to triangulate the stations position.  The station is attacked when the protagonist and a junior man are off taking core samples.  Upon returning, they find the station totally destroyed and the commander barely clinging onto life.  As they race for the northern peninsula, the adventure begins.  If they don’t make it in time, the ice will make rescue impossible.  And a winter without a proper shelter is impossible to survive in this harsh continent.  In the end, only one man survives.  He claims to have lost his memory of the events before his rescue and he longs to return.  Then we are able to learn why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have often wondered why anyone would want to visit or live in Antarctica.  It seems like a barren place, devoid of life.  But this book has shown me the beauty and wonder of that most untouched of our continents.  I did not realize the amount of life existing during the summer months, that can exceed almost all other places on earth during the peak.  It was truly a memorable story that was as shocking at time as it was touching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one complaint that I have about the book.  It seems quite petty, but it was a major detraction as I was really getting into it.  The setting is 1942.  I am in a mindset of World War Two.  All surrounding are described with the technology available then.  The tent material wasn’t modern day synthetics.  However, the penguins jumping over a 5 feet ridge are described as “jump jets”.  This really hit me wrong.  I was taken out of the 1940’s mindset and propelled back to modern day, with one poorly chosen metaphor.  This is a minor issue and you will certainly enjoy the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>A Crossing: A Cyclist’s Journey Home by Brian Newhouse</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/a-cyclists-journey-home/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2007-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-09:/blog/reviews/a-cyclists-journey-home/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 156px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/cyclejourneyhome.jpg" style="width: 156px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an incredible read.  Brian starts his trek by dipping his wheel in the Pacific Ocean and heading east.
Follow Brian across the United States and learn of his internal conflicts and pressures that time
alone on a bicycle set free.  Raised in a fundimentalist Christian home, he is searching for the
method of understanding his relationship with his father and his spirituality.You do not have to ride a bicycle to enjoy this book.
I have not …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 156px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/cyclejourneyhome.jpg" style="width: 156px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an incredible read.  Brian starts his trek by dipping his wheel in the Pacific Ocean and heading east.
Follow Brian across the United States and learn of his internal conflicts and pressures that time
alone on a bicycle set free.  Raised in a fundimentalist Christian home, he is searching for the
method of understanding his relationship with his father and his spirituality.You do not have to ride a bicycle to enjoy this book.
I have not found a story that better describes the complex characteristics
men use to shield and suppress their emotions.  Towards the end, I was broken up as some of Brian’s
relationship with his father mirrored mine.  This book has been a catalyst in changing those parts of my relationship
that were lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let me make you think that the entire book is a serious soul searching saga.  The crisp description of this cross country experience is dotted with experiences and characters such as the First Church of the Absurb member, Brian runs into along the way.
While there are some stories during the trip that I wish were more developed, I think
you will enjoy reading through this deeply touching book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;288 pages, Paperback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 1998&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published by Pocket Books&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Metal Cowboy by Joe Kurmaskie</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/metal-cowboy-by-joe-kurmaskie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2007-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-11-04:/blog/reviews/metal-cowboy-by-joe-kurmaskie/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/metal-cowboy.jpeg" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not found a way to better describe this book than the first sentence inside the dust cover. “It’s as if Dave Barry and Charles Kuralt squeezed together onto a bicycle to pedal across America and around the world, filing outrageous dispatches along the way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, many times while reading I felt as if I was watching the well done Sunday morning stories where the common man or the small town are shown in all of their glory.  Those stories that aren’t as touching will give you a great laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/metal-cowboy.jpeg" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not found a way to better describe this book than the first sentence inside the dust cover. “It’s as if Dave Barry and Charles Kuralt squeezed together onto a bicycle to pedal across America and around the world, filing outrageous dispatches along the way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, many times while reading I felt as if I was watching the well done Sunday morning stories where the common man or the small town are shown in all of their glory.  Those stories that aren’t as touching will give you a great laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aspiring bicycle tourist, this book was hard for me to put down.  I can give a book no better compliment than to say that it followed me to lunch and dinner every day for a week.  The only problem I had was trying to cope with the fact that I would not be able to start any serious bicycle touring until I left on my Trans-Am tour in May of 2002.  This book made me want to be out on the road &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOW&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metal Cowboy is a collection of short stories, which makes it very easy to read in small bites.  You should ask yourself if you can really miss out on Joe accidentally tricking an entire town that he is Kiefer Sutherland.  How do you outrun the Paparazzi on a bicycle?  Or have you ever been attacked by killer geese while riding?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been able to talk with Joe Kurmaskie over e-mail, as he is a member of the touring list (no longer around).  There is good news for those interested in reading about more Metal Cowboy adventures.  He asked me about the quote in my e-mail signature.   Joe may be using it to open his next book.  Here is part of an e-mail from Joe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;Glad to hear you’re enjoying my campfire stories… I’m knee deep into completing edits and polishing the second collection in the continuing adventures of yours truly and the open road. This next batch, titled &lt;em&gt;On Yere Bike, More Adventures With The Metal Cowboy&lt;/em&gt; takes us through Ireland, more Australia, Alaska and Yukon tales… bounty hunters and vicious ping pong players in South America and  a round of Mexican Jeopardy  during  intermission of a bull fight in La Paz Mexico, among other things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure that Joe has many more stories to tell and I know he can tell those stories with gusto.  (Reposting this a few years after writing it, Joe now has 3 books out about adventures in cycling.  I just ordered the two I haven’t read yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="nonfiction"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Deception Point by Dan Brown</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/deception-point-by-dan-brown/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2007-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-06-02:/blog/reviews/deception-point-by-dan-brown/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/deception-point.jpg" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; was the first book of Dan Brown’s I read.  It seemed like your only choice was to read the book, due to popularity.  I really enjoy Brown’s style of writing, but didn’t like the far stretches required to make &lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; a suspenseful novel and much of the false history.  I guess it didn’t really bug me when reading the book.  The thing that bugged me was people thinking it was the truth after reading a &lt;strong&gt;fictional&lt;/strong&gt; novel.  Despite this, when seeing &lt;em&gt;Deception Point&lt;/em&gt; for sale at our United Way book sale at work, I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deception Point&lt;/em&gt; involves the discovery of an astonishingly rare object buried deep in arctic ice in the far North.  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;, in dire need of a success to halt a funding cut or complete elimination of the organization, are careful to pull in civilian scientists to validate their discovery beyond a shadow of doubt.  In addition, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; analyst Rachel Sexton is brought in as a professional skeptic.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/deception-point.jpg" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; was the first book of Dan Brown’s I read.  It seemed like your only choice was to read the book, due to popularity.  I really enjoy Brown’s style of writing, but didn’t like the far stretches required to make &lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; a suspenseful novel and much of the false history.  I guess it didn’t really bug me when reading the book.  The thing that bugged me was people thinking it was the truth after reading a &lt;strong&gt;fictional&lt;/strong&gt; novel.  Despite this, when seeing &lt;em&gt;Deception Point&lt;/em&gt; for sale at our United Way book sale at work, I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deception Point&lt;/em&gt; involves the discovery of an astonishingly rare object buried deep in arctic ice in the far North.  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;, in dire need of a success to halt a funding cut or complete elimination of the organization, are careful to pull in civilian scientists to validate their discovery beyond a shadow of doubt.  In addition, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; analyst Rachel Sexton is brought in as a professional skeptic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incumbent President is loosing in the polls to Senator Sexton, Rachel’s father. Because there is no love lost between Rachel and her dad, it will be a powerful strike against Senator Sexton if his daughter verifies the accuracy of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;’s find, an organization he wishes to eliminate. Unfortunate for Rachel and the civilian scientists, they discover some trickery in the scientific discovery.  The question is if they can get away from the special forces assassins now tasked to kill them, before the world can be made aware of this scam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paperback is 557 pages long, but it was a rapid read.  Brown’s prose is efficient.   By that I mean he describes what is needed, but doesn’t fill the book with overly colorful and boring descriptions.  I’m a firm believer that you can give a small description of characters and then use the story to flesh them out.  Brown does this well, in contrast to a book I just put down yet again, because of the 50 pages of exposition in the start that I am still failing to get through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an Engineer, I enjoy some of the technical discussion in the book. I’m actually not sure what is real and what he made up.   Don’t worry if you  are not a technical person.  It is all well explained and not detracting of the story at all.  Even his made up details have a ring of truth to them, which was lacking at times in &lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>The Code Book by Simon Singh</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/the-code-book-by-simon-singh/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-03-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2007-03-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-03-23:/blog/reviews/the-code-book-by-simon-singh/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/the-code-book.jpg" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry, you can no longer win $15,000 by reading this book.  It was the announcement of the solution to the 10 cipher challenges, located in the back of &lt;em&gt;The Code Book&lt;/em&gt;, that made me aware of this book.  Money aside, if you are interested in learning of the history of codes and ciphers, this book is for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that Mary Queens of Scots was killed by Queen Elizabeth, because her code was not strong enough to foil the code breakers of the time.  Have you ever heard of the Navajo Code Talkers that offered the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; Marines a method of secure ground communications in World War &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt;?  (Probably more so after the Windtalkers movie.)  Do you know the full story behind the breaking of the German’s Enigma Code in the same war?  Do you know that the first computer was build in England, not the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/the-code-book.jpg" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry, you can no longer win $15,000 by reading this book.  It was the announcement of the solution to the 10 cipher challenges, located in the back of &lt;em&gt;The Code Book&lt;/em&gt;, that made me aware of this book.  Money aside, if you are interested in learning of the history of codes and ciphers, this book is for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that Mary Queens of Scots was killed by Queen Elizabeth, because her code was not strong enough to foil the code breakers of the time.  Have you ever heard of the Navajo Code Talkers that offered the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; Marines a method of secure ground communications in World War &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt;?  (Probably more so after the Windtalkers movie.)  Do you know the full story behind the breaking of the German’s Enigma Code in the same war?  Do you know that the first computer was build in England, not the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew most of the above facts before reading this book.  However, as with most people’s understanding of history, my ideas were seriously flawed in the details.  This book allows you to start out with the world’s earliest codes and learn how to do a little code breaking of your own.  If you are at all interested in either the technical or historical history of code breaking, you will enjoy this book.  This is the first technical history book that read like a good piece of fiction.  When you realize that the action packed stories are historical fact, the book only shines more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="nonfiction"></category></entry><entry><title>Sew and Repair Your Outdoor Gear by Louise Lindgren</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/sew-and-repair-your-outdoor-gear-by-louise-lindgren/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2007-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-02-14:/blog/reviews/sew-and-repair-your-outdoor-gear-by-louise-lindgren/</id><summary type="html">
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/sew-repair.jpg" style="width: 180px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really wish I had ran into this book before I purchased my “utility” sewing machine.  I got a no frills home machine with a few stitches.  It was a floor model, but I would have been better to spend the money on a light weight industrial sewing machine with only a straight stitch.  Louise was talking about me when she mentioned those who buy a machine with all of these cool stitches.   They play with these stitches for a month and then only sew straight seams.  I now wish I had a machine that just sews straight seams like a champ.  I’m glad I got my machine pretty cheap, as I’ll most likely upgrade now that I am having fun making stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 180px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/sew-repair.jpg" style="width: 180px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really wish I had ran into this book before I purchased my “utility” sewing machine.  I got a no frills home machine with a few stitches.  It was a floor model, but I would have been better to spend the money on a light weight industrial sewing machine with only a straight stitch.  Louise was talking about me when she mentioned those who buy a machine with all of these cool stitches.   They play with these stitches for a month and then only sew straight seams.  I now wish I had a machine that just sews straight seams like a champ.  I’m glad I got my machine pretty cheap, as I’ll most likely upgrade now that I am having fun making stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is a great read for anyone who wants to build or maintain gear.  The opening of the book goes something like: This is the book I wish I had when I started sewing and repairing outdoor gear many years ago.  I am glad I did have it.  It explains many things that I have always wondered about.  I didn’t know if heat sealing and edge was better or worse than serging.  She explains the reasons why most garments you purchase have certain seams.  It is usually because that is the fastest seam to sew that is “good enough” for the application.  If you take a little time at your home machine, you can make seams that rival commercially produced sewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of writing this review, I have finished one pannier, using many of the techniques described in the book.  I’m looking forward to a few more projects, including a couple from patterns in this book.  There is a stuff bag pattern that is a simple rectangle of fabric sized based on the width and circumference of the equipment you want to stuff.  I makes a square bottom and is much easier to make than the typical round bottom stuff bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, if you are thinking about sewing outdoor gear, it is worth the $17 and your time to read through this book.  This helped my create &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/how-to/how-to-build-bicycle-panniers/"&gt;my own custom bike bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="nonfiction"></category></entry><entry><title>The Bicycle Wheel by Jobst Brandt</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/the-bicycle-wheel-by-jobst-brandt/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2002-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-03-02:/blog/reviews/the-bicycle-wheel-by-jobst-brandt/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 185px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/the-bicycle-wheel.gif" style="width: 185px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have just finished building my first rear wheel using &lt;em&gt;The Bicycle Wheel&lt;/em&gt; as a guide.  This book will teach you the technical aspects of the bicycle wheel in both structural principles and practical methods.  After a couple hundred miles on my new wheel, it is still true as an arrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book debunks myths and gives you the confidence to repair, build, and rebuild wheels.  I can honestly say that I no longer fear any wheel repairs.  It has …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 185px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/the-bicycle-wheel.gif" style="width: 185px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have just finished building my first rear wheel using &lt;em&gt;The Bicycle Wheel&lt;/em&gt; as a guide.  This book will teach you the technical aspects of the bicycle wheel in both structural principles and practical methods.  After a couple hundred miles on my new wheel, it is still true as an arrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book debunks myths and gives you the confidence to repair, build, and rebuild wheels.  I can honestly say that I no longer fear any wheel repairs.  It has given me one less thing to worry about during my upcoming cross-country trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only warning I can give is about Jobst Brandt, not his book.  If you run across him in the Newsgroup or in person, you will quickly find out that he is a very opinionated person.  Most of his opinions are correct, but don”t ever argue with him.  Jobst has to be one of the bigger know-it-all jerks I have seen on the Usenet.  I guess everyone has their failings, but his book is first rate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="book review"></category><category term="nonfiction"></category><category term="cycling"></category></entry></feed>