<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>joesacher.com</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/feeds/reviews.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.joesacher.com/</id><updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Playing for Pizza by John Grisham</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/playing-for-pizza-by-john-grisham/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-08-02:blog/reviews/playing-for-pizza-by-john-grisham/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/playing-for-pizza.jpg" style="width: 164px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I was intrigued when I read the summary of this book.  A novel by John Grisham about a third string &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; quarterback, escaping his terrible past to play professional football in Italy.  Nothing about lawyers?  This sounds interesting, if not just to figure out why John described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally the novel isn’t quite as good, when an author writes completely out of their “comfort zone”.  That is definitely the case here.  It doesn’t have the same fire as a typical Grisham thriller.  That isn’t to say it is a bad book.  I enjoyed the read and it was fun to see a different side of this author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts with Rick Dockery in a hospital bed, after the worst game of his varied &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; career.  In the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFC&lt;/span&gt; Championship game, this third string player is forced into the game with 11 minutes left.  The Browns are up 20-0.  Rick manages to toss enough interceptions to loose the game and Cleveland’s Super Bowl ticket.  The last hit of the game mercifully knocks him senseless and offers a day with no memory of what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All bridges burned, Rick’s only available job is playing for the Parma Panthers in Italy, where American Football ranks at near the bottom of all sports.  Games are free, yet less than a couple hundred attend.  Only three Americans are allowed per team and they are the only players paid any money.  It seemed like the same as a Softball league in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;, a proud hobby to most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The description of the four hour Italian meals made me want to go to Italy, just for the food.  It was obvious that Grisham had spent some time in Italy and really wanted to give the read an appreciation of the country.  I wish his character development was as endearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rick is a typical womanizing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; player at the start of the novel.  He doesn’t seem to change.  Some of the characters are fleshed out well, but most are flat.  It is a story about an American &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFL&lt;/span&gt; player in Italy.  That is it.  The plot could have used much more development and choices for story direction at times were just boring.  The romance near the end of the book is empty.  I felt that Rick and his girlfriend were together because it was convenient.  I had hoped for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book would have been harder to get published, if written by a non-famous author.    If you are not a fan of football, you will probably not enjoy this novel.  Most of the conflicts and growth occur only in relation to football.  Rick doesn’t grow much as a person, otherwise.  It is worth reading and is a short and quick book.  I think the library is a great place to get a copy, because you probably won’t want to read it again.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>Treason by Don Brown</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/treason-by-don-brown/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-08-02:blog/reviews/treason-by-don-brown/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 170px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/Treason-DonBrown.png" style="width: 170px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This used to be offered as a free book for the Kindle and was one of many I added to my account after receiving my Kindle. (If its free, its for me, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reading the author “Don Brown” on the cover of this novel, I was mistaking it for a more famous Dan Brown (Da Vinci Code). As I read the military themes unfold, my mind then played further tricks on me as I made a connection with Dale Brown’s military styled novels as the author.  None of this is important in discussing the merits and faults of this novel, which shares more with John Grisham than either of the other two authors mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Treason&lt;/em&gt; is the first book in Don Brown’s Navy Justice series, which follows Navy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; (Judge Advocate General) Lieutenant Zack Brewer through two major cases.  This feels familiar to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; series. Don Brown is a former &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; Officer and thus the similarities between the two are actually similarities between both and the actual Military Justice System of the United States.  All interactions and procedures portrayed in the book seem real and believable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an average novel, but not a great one. I was confused by the level of discussion of faith throughout the book, tempered mostly by my assumption that the author was one of those discussed above. It was surprising that they would break form and include some discussion of Christian faith and beliefs, when not directly germane to the plot. As a Christian, I actually enjoyed what it added to the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the novel, I realized that the publisher is Zondervan, one of the largest Bible and Evangelical Christian book publishers.  Thus the inclusion of Christian themes is less surprising.  I actually found it much more subtle than other novels with tangential Christian teaching which I have read in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard not to compare this book to works from John Grisham, who is after all a master of the courtroom novel. Unfortunately, Don Brown does not quite make the cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel opens with Muslim leaders discussing the infiltration of sleeper agents into the United States Armed Forces.  As the story unfolds, we learn that a lawsuit was won which allowed Muslim Chaplains into the Armed Forces. Some of these Chaplains are handlers to infiltrate and create a network of like minded Muslim soldiers to attack the enemy from within.  This is truly a scary premise and one which is an undeniably fertile ground for a great story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muslim soldiers are committing acts of terror.  One instance, a soldier brings grenades to a Christian church where a discussion of Islam was occurring.  The bomber demands that the preacher admit that Mohammed is the one true prophet and explodes two grenades when the preacher stands his ground.  Many are killed, along with the attacker. In a second instance, a sniper assassinates the Ambassador from Israel, before committing suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first trial in the book is mostly for setting the ball rolling and introducing the main players.  A Navy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SEAL&lt;/span&gt; is accused of raping an officer, who is the niece of a prominent Senator.  I found it amusing that the novel included a token “Reverend” whose only preaching occurs by talking about oppressed minorities to the press. This just rings a little too true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zach is prosecuting the case against a beautiful &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAG&lt;/span&gt; officer, who hates Zach due to a previous encounter.  Throughout the trial, the truth is unknown. The rape accusation sounds fishy and Zach is troubled by his thought that he might not be doing the correct thing in putting the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SEAL&lt;/span&gt; away. Unfortunately, this theme is almost immediately dropped at the conclusion of the first trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a F-18 Hornet is destroyed by another jihadist, who plants explosives in the fighter. This is the event which starts the investigation of the main case in the novel.  The United States vs the 3 Chaplains who ran the jihadists in the military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we have cross plots of possible future political aspirations of the young Lieutenant Zack with a possible pairing with the famous Senator’s niece.  The problem is the main meat and potatoes of the novel is the second trial.  This is where the novel falters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President of the United States allows cameras into the courtroom for the first time in a Court Marshal. I initially wondered why and realized later that it was for the benefit of the writer. Far too often, when major portions of the case were to happen, the plot was moved forward by tangential characters hearing the summary on the evening news.  It seems as though the author assumed all readers would skim this part anyway, so he did the skimming for them.  The drama is in the courtroom: what is said, what is done.  The novel is lesser for leaving much of this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it is a novel I enjoyed reading, but wouldn’t read again. The plot was predictable and linear. Characters one dimensional with little ambiguity. Everything is very black and white. I assumed the ending in the first few chapters and unfortunately was absolutely correct.  Surprises were few and far between.  I my eventually read the other two books in this series, but I’m in not rush to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry><entry><title>Jet Mini vs PSI Turncrafter Pro</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/a-lathe-comparison-jet-mini-vs-psi-turncrafter-pro/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-26:blog/reviews/a-lathe-comparison-jet-mini-vs-psi-turncrafter-pro/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was looking at lathes, I talked with many people who had tried and liked either the Jet Mini or the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; Turncrafter Pro lathes. I could not find many that had used both, to get an idea of the differences between them. Now owning a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; Turncrafter Pro and having taken a class and used a Jet Mini for 5 hours or so, I decided to summarize the differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both lathes look deceptively similar. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; is 4” longer in the bed at 18”, vs 14” for the Jet. The Jet also has one higher speed. The first 5 speed ranges seem to be very close. The beds look almost exactly the same, as do the banjo and steady rest. The motor height adjustment is almost exactly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality wise, the Jet has a nicer finish and features. By this, I mean the machining is a little better cleaned up and parts are more thought out. The threads on my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; headstock looked like there were cut and never touched again. There are burrs and sharp edges that I will be dressing down. While the Jet lathe I was using had been in use at the classroom for a while, I haven”t noticed this on Jet minis out on display at shops either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major difference, which will affect daily use, are the belt access doors. The Jet has a nice flip open door for both top and bottom access. Although the spring handle setup for the bottom door seems a little strange to me, it works fast once you get used to it. The access to the belts are in exactly the same spot, but the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; has a thumb screw to undo and then a little plastic piece which is lifted and removed. This piece has slits on the bottom that sits on bolts screwed in below the opening. The piece would be set down for the change then replaced. It makes for a piece to lose and takes over twice as long to change the belt speed as on the Jet. I will be replacing my plastic pieces with doors that have a spring clip, similar to the Jet’s. Currently my access panels are off, because they are annoying to remove and replace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The locking handle on the steady rest and the tail stock depth lock are both a plastic handles on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt;. The operation is the same, both spring loaded handles which can be lifted to change position. The plastic handles don’t feel flimsy, but I doubt they will last quite as long as the metal handles on the Jet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point to point, my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; is slightly off (1/32” tail is closer to me than the head point).  While a thin shim under the tail will fix this, I”m not sure if this is typical with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; or not. My sample size is 1. I did not see this with the 4 Jet lathes I looked at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still happy with my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt; purchase. After I spend a little bit of time to polish off some of the rough edges and I will have a nice lathe for about $100 less than the Jet. I don’t see the loss of the high end (3800 rpm or so) on the Jet as too much of a problem. 3200 rpm is fast enough and both have the 500 rpm low end. But there is no doubt, the Jet is a better finished machine, with a few upgrades over the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt;. If I could have found the Jet on special for within $20-40 of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSI&lt;/span&gt;, I would have paid the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="woodworking"></category><category term="lathes"></category></entry><entry><title>Bicycling Coast to Coast</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/bicycling-coast-to-coast/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-15:blog/reviews/bicycling-coast-to-coast/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/bicycling-coast-to-coast.jpg" style="width: 128px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I realized that my recumbent would allow me to complete my dream of riding a bicycle across the country, I started research all over the web.  While reading through the many trip reports of coast to coast touring cyclists, two things became clear.  First, I would be riding the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org/routes/transamerica.cfm"&gt;TransAmerica trail&lt;/a&gt; created by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org"&gt;Adventure Cycling&lt;/a&gt; in 1976 (the year of my birth).  Second, I should purchase, read, re-read, and take along Donna’s book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read through Donna’s book at least once.  It is divided into 82 days worth of riding to cross the country, so I often will read a few of the day accounts at a time.  Normally I read sections to compare and contrast them with other on-line travelogues, jotting notes in the book.  Each day has a literary description of the ride, followed with turn by turn directions and points of interest.  This book was published in 1996, so you should not take it as gospel that “Joe Blowe’s Convienient Mart” will still be there.  As an adventure cyclist, you wouldn’t always want to know, would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book can get you across the country without a problem, however, you should use it along with the excellent &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adventurecycling.org/routes/"&gt;maps&lt;/a&gt; provided by Adventure Cycling.  These maps are a cyclist dream, without all of the pitfalls contained in standard road maps.  Do you wonder which of the nearest towns have a bike shop, or a post office, or a laundry mat?  It’s on the map.  The many Adventure Cycling trips across the country every year keep the maps as up to date as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m left in May of 2002, with this book in my bag, to spend &lt;a class="reference external" href='http://www.joesacher.com/category/trans-am.html'&gt;4 months riding across this great country of ours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When are you leaving?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0898864682?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;tag=joesacher-20&amp;amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;amp;creativeASIN=0898864682"&gt;Bicycling Coast to Coast: A Complete Route Guide Virginia to Oregon  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;: 0898864682 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book review"></category><category term="nonfiction"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>White-Out by James Vance Marshall</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/white-out-by-james-vance-marshall/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-11:blog/reviews/white-out-by-james-vance-marshall/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/book-review/white-out.jpg" style="width: 161px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book I happened on by chance.  I picked it out of the new book section of the library by the title and checked it out after reading the inside cover.  I’m glad that I did.  While I only rate it 4 out of 5, it was an interesting book and worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is centered on telling the story of a Royal Navy officer and his trials to survive against impossible odds.  The main story is set during the Second World War on the continent of Antarctica.  The British Royal Navy sends a small force to establish a weather station while also carrying out a top-secret mission.  A German U-Boat intercepts the periodic weather forecasts and is able to triangulate the stations position.  The station is attacked when the protagonist and a junior man are off taking core samples.  Upon returning, they find the station totally destroyed and the commander barely clinging onto life.  As they race for the northern peninsula, the adventure begins.  If they don’t make it in time, the ice will make rescue impossible.  And a winter without a proper shelter is impossible to survive in this harsh continent.  In the end, only one man survives.  He claims to have lost his memory of the events before his rescue and he longs to return.  Then we are able to learn why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have often wondered why anyone would want to visit or live in Antarctica.  It seems like a barren place, devoid of life.  But this book has shown me the beauty and wonder of that most untouched of our continents.  I did not realize the amount of life existing during the summer months, that can exceed almost all other places on earth during the peak.  It was truly a memorable story that was as shocking at time as it was touching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one complaint that I have about the book.  It seems quite petty, but it was a major detraction as I was really getting into it.  The setting is 1942.  I am in a mindset of World War Two.  All surrounding are described with the technology available then.  The tent material wasn’t modern day synthetics.  However, the penguins jumping over a 5 feet ridge are described as “jump jets”.  This really hit me wrong.  I was taken out of the 1940’s mindset and propelled back to modern day, with one poorly chosen metaphor.  This is a minor issue and you will certainly enjoy the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book review"></category><category term="fiction"></category></entry></feed>