<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>joesacher.com</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/feeds/tech.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.joesacher.com/</id><updated>2012-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>The Windows Phone Experiment is Over</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/tech/windows-phone-experiment-is-over/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2012-04-09:blog/tech/windows-phone-experiment-is-over/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My wife and I left webOS when &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; flushed their 3 year plan to revamp webOS down the toilet. We tested both Android and Windows Phone. Android is a multitasking joke.
Coming from webOS, it has a terrible &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UI&lt;/span&gt;. Windows Phone has very nice flowing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UI&lt;/span&gt;. We decided to go to Windows Phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft representatives promised to get phones and development credits to webOS programmers. Despite many requests, it turned out to be a bunch of hot air.
Sadly, this turned me off to all mobile development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We slugged along with trying to make Windows Phone a viable mobile solution for 8 months. We are done trying. After two weeks of switching to Android, we know two things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android is painful to use, compared to the grace of webOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LESS&lt;/span&gt; painful than Windows Phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy podcasts. Trying to listen to them on Windows Phone is a complete nightmare. It is so bad that I stopped listening to podcasts completely.
It was one of the many things I slowly gave up, because of the lack of usability on Windows Phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a decent collection of audio books on mp3 format. There is only one way that I could make these work on Windows Phone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join all mp3s in the right order into one mp3 file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the metadata to indicate podcast genre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go through Zune to get it on my phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then if I want to listen to other things on the device, I get to lose my place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to subscribe to audio books on Audible. I stopped with webOS.
This keeps getting promised for Windows Phone. This exists for Android. Which brings us into another factor: apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dealt with the lack of apps, lack of access to hardware, lack of many things on webOS, because the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UI&lt;/span&gt; is still the best out there.
Two weeks on Android with access to some of the things I have been missing, makes up for a lot of bad &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UI&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zune slowly changed from something I have to work through to get stuff on my phone, to something that drove me completely nuts.
I setup WiFi sync, so that I didn’t have to constantly connect my phone to download podcasts and other things to it.
My Windows Phone almost never correctly download these things on its own. Oh, how many times I watched my phone indicate pending downloads that would never come to pass.
WiFi worked to finish the downloads when the software felt merciful and the moon was in the correct region of the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted an annoying piece of software that was the gatekeeper for my device, I would just deal with the abomination that is iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;File management is a joke. The process of getting a document on and off your phone involves crazy steps of using email, online syncs, and a bit of prayer.
I miss the former days of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; drive mode, where I could just copy files. Guess what? That is back with Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Windows Phone has the same multi-task pausing of the iPhone, it was easier to switch between apps than Android. However, if the app isn’t setup with the Mango resume,
the pause before the app resumes is annoying. Really the two platforms are pretty much tied in this race. They both have barely left the starting blocks of usability, compared to webOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought that the home screen of Android would be more annoying. It turns out to be less so than trying to fit all the apps you want to use on the start screen or looking them up each time in the alphabetical list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do I have with Android now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps for my credit union, including deposit check via photo. Charging credit cards via a device on the headphone jack. Tethering via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; for free.
Not quite the WiFi hot spot that webOS gave me, but I can have that too if I decide to root the phone. Edit: Found FoxFi, so WiFi hot spot is back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video player that plays files I just drop on the phone via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;. No waiting 30 minutes to convert the files into the correct format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambling Book Player that takes an audio book with 250 files and handles it perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeyondPod which, while not as nice as Dr. Podder on webOS, can actually manager all my podcasting needs on the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audible. I have missed Audible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ScummVM is now back on my phone. I was one of the backers for Double Fine’s Adventure game on Kickstarter. I enjoy these things. It was possible with webOS, and now is again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are far from perfect on my Android transition. I have to periodically hit the optimize button to close down rogue apps.
I had to get a 3500 mAh battery to make my phone last a day. But things are better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;P.S.&lt;/span&gt; I found out that Zune doesn’t want me to go. I cancelled our Zune Pass. Luckily, I had a card stolen and cancelled that card as well.
Now I get an email periodically about how the card is bad. How they can’t charge a monthly fee for a service I cancelled over 2 weeks ago. Zune, the relationship is over.  We broke up.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="mobile"></category><category term="windows phone"></category></entry><entry><title>Zune Podcasts - A Rant</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/tech/zune-podcasts-a-rant/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-09-21:blog/tech/zune-podcasts-a-rant/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Zune podcast functionality on Windows Phone Mango was obviously designed by someone who never listens to podcasts.  I’ve tried to use it over the last three weeks and it is an exercise in futility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one glaring problems that needs to be addressed before it is close to usable.  It all comes down to episode management.  Unfortunately, this is the most important factor of any podcast solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Order is allowed, for either oldest first or newest first.  This is great.  What this means is that it will constantly download the oldest or the newest.  Doesn’t matter how many times you have heard them.
It doesn’t matter if you manually marked them as heard and manually deleted them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have oldest selected, guess what is downloading back on the phone?  Do you remember those old favorites that you have manually deleted 10 times already?  Yeah, they’re back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello old friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are caught up and always listen to the latest, the moment it comes out, then having the newest set and keeping the latest X on your devices works fine.
Myself, I set almost everything to oldest, because if 2 episodes come out before I get back to that podcast, I want to hear them in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t that hard.  When a feed is added, a piece of data is tracked for each episode.  If you have downloaded and listened to a podcast, store the podcast filename or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; with a played flag.
When you are listing episodes, you put a small indicator that this is old and listened to already.  When syncing podcasts, download the oldest or newest that don’t have the listened to flag set.  Done.
This is programming, not rocket science.  The user can manually redownload them if wanted, but otherwise they are dead to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a database that remembers which are played, can we mark them as played without downloading them?  Pretty please?
Some podcasts were online before you were even a glint in your compiler’s linked binaries.  I’m at episode 140 of 200, but selecting oldest will only allow me to start at 1.
Even if episodes were marked as listened correctly, I would have to download and mark all 139 prior episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, can we ask for another great feature?  Add an auto delete after listening option.  Wouldn’t that be great?  You listen to an episode.  It is marked as played in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DB&lt;/span&gt; and deleted.  Now what happens?
The next episode is automatically downloaded to get up to your keep at least number.  It would be almost like the software was reading my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve almost stopped listening to PodCasts on Windows Phone, because the management of episodes is more work than the enjoyment of listening to them.
Maybe it is too easy to spot really crappy software after using really great software.   If anyone wants to see really good software, look at drPodder on webOS.
It is open source, take a look.  It makes Zune’s implementation looks like a bad student programming project.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="podcasts"></category><category term="mobile"></category><category term="windows phone"></category></entry><entry><title>Android vs Windows Phone Navigation</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/tech/android-vs-windows-phone-navigation/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-09-07:blog/tech/android-vs-windows-phone-navigation/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m testing both Android and Windows Phone on Sprint.  Both devices have free TeleNav service on Sprint, so the service using that application is roughly similar.  Both phones also come with stock turn by turn directions.
Android is a no holds barred knockout win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turn by turn directions in pre-Mango Windows Phone is a joke.  You must tap the screen to move along, making it totally unusable for navigation when you are driving the car.  The Mango update provides considerably increased driving instructions.
If you follow the route given, the system works very well.  If you do not, you will soon want to through your phone out your car window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have used each phone’s direction solution to “find” my way to work.  Due to heavy construction, the fastest route is not obvious.  This is a good way of figuring out how annoying &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; software will be, by driving in a manner that it considers idiotic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first day was with Android 2.3.5.  I started Navigation, tapped Speak Navigation, and rattled off my work address.  It parsed the address correctly.  I deviated from the proposed route no less than ten times.
When I went off route, the phone didn’t utter a peep, it just recalculated a route faster than any mapping solution I have ever used.  Voice prompts were there when needed, but not annoying at all.
After determining that the routing works as well as TeleNav, this would be my preferred navigation solution on Android.  TeleNav give you a speak destination option, but it does not parse the speech to text as well as Navigate.
If you want to use TeleNav for the routing, you can let Navigate hear your location then select which you wish to use for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; routing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second day was with Windows Phone 7.5 beta.  I started Maps and tapped the directions arrow, then typed in my work address.  Then I started navigating.  No voice destination is available in Maps or TeleNav.
The routing looks fine.  Now I go off route.  My phone tells me that I have gone off track and I can tap the screen to reroute.  Excuse me?  I have to tap the screen to reroute?
Whoever came up with this idea is the same guy who puts 2 “Are you &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SURE&lt;/span&gt; you want to close this App?” dialogs, when you just want to get out of the program.
So I held the phone in my hand, because I knew I would have to tap the screen after each mile or so leg, when it thinks I should get “back on track”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wound up turning off Maps about halfway to work, to keep me from throwing the phone out the window.  A complete and utter usability failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android wins this round.  Still not sure if it is enough to get past the complete ease of use failure that is the Android system in general, so I’m still using both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…and still missing webOS.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="windows phone"></category><category term="gps"></category><category term="navigation"></category></entry><entry><title>Windows Phone Podcast Experience</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/tech/windows-phone-podcast-experience/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-09-07:blog/tech/windows-phone-podcast-experience/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The “Mango” update for Windows Phone, or version 7.5 for those less fruity, adds many features.  This article is dealing with the podcasting capabilities.  On webOS, I made daily use of a brilliant piece of software called drPodder.
Moving from this almost clairvoyant app to the integrated podcast ability of Windows Phone is quite jarring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be outlining the current successes and fails with Windows Phone which keep it from being an enjoyable podcasting experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="adding-podcasts"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adding podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding podcasts from the device is only possible by searching the Zune podcast library.  If the podcast does not exists in the library, you cannot add it from the phone.
If you have an obscure podcast, you can add an rss feed through the Zune desktop software.  Not at all ideal, but it does work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="playback-order-win"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Playback Order (Win)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting up a podcast, you can specify the number of episodes you wish to download to the phone at a time and the order (oldest or newest first.)  This makes sense.
Some podcasts are episodic and it would be confusing to listen to them in anything but chronological order.  News podcasts might make more sense to listen to the latest first and the older if you have time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what happens when you want to listen to them from oldest to newest for a podcast that has been out for years?  That brings us to…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="episode-management-fail"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Episode Management (Fail)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listen to many podcasts that have been around far before Windows Phone was a twinkle in a cell carrier’s eyes.  So I setup a new podcast that I am up to episode 107 on my current device.  I listen to it oldest first and set a sync of 3.
My Windows Phone will download Episodes 1, 2, and 3.  Then I can tap hold and mark as read.  However, I cannot do this until the episode is downloaded.  So the process of catching up is to download each episode and mark it as read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tap and hold an undownloaded, unplayed episode should have an option to mark as played.  Ideally, there would be some functionality to “catch up” and mark all as played.
This would be more useful in a majority of cases when you are transitioning from a device where you have been a loyal listener.  If you set all to read and then have to reset the last 2 or 3 to unread, this is still a faster experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="video-support-win"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video Support (Win)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Windows Phone handles video podcasts very well.  Playback is crisp in visuals and program performance and start up time.  I don”t see anything in video that is a problem, other than the problems also common to any style podcast in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bookmarks-occasional-fail"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bookmarks (occasional Fail)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podcasts are much longer than songs.  It is not uncommon for them to pass 90 minutes.  Most people won”t listen to them at one sitting.  The podcast player should remember time into each episode of each show to which a listener has progressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bookmarks seem to work as expected in video podcasts.  However, I have had mixed results with audio, with many times getting no bookmark.  Instead of a complete oversight, which I originally assumed, it seems to be bugs in the process.
What I am running is still beta code, so we will have to wait to see if this is addressed in the version of Mango sent down to phones.  If you play from the main screen and are careful to pause, it seems to work.  Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a2dp-bluetooth-support-fail"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;A2DP&lt;/span&gt; Bluetooth Support (Fail)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Bluetooth support on Windows Phone is woefully lacking, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;A2DP&lt;/span&gt; profile seems to work perfectly for any audio only component.  When you bring video into the mix, nothing you do will make audio stream through your Bluetooth device.
This affects video podcasts along with all video on the device, including YouTube, local videos, and Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you will watch no video on the phone, you will find &lt;span class="caps"&gt;A2DP&lt;/span&gt; to satisfy you.  But with only partial support, you have no choice other than to use wired headphones if you consume any video at all.  This makes &lt;span class="caps"&gt;A2DP&lt;/span&gt; worthless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="streaming-win"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Streaming (Win)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to listen to an episode that you have not downloaded, no problem.  Streaming the episode worked great for both audio and video playback.  As long as you used those wired headphones for the video, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="control-from-other-apps-win"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Control from Other Apps (Win)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Windows Phone is not anywhere close to the multitasking that was enjoyed in webOS, they control of audio playback while moving around other apps works well.
If you at inside another application and wish to pause playback (or other controls, such as skipping a track) you simply hit either volume button.  The first touch of a volume button does not change the volume, but drops down a media control panel.
From here you can pause and go forward or back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting past the pain of catching up all the shows, it should work fine for steady state listening.  Heaven help me if I ever get behind again and just want to catch up.  I’ll be using this for my daily podcasts for a while and see how it goes.
Sure wish I could get my missing podcasts back though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="windows phone"></category><category term="podcasts"></category></entry><entry><title>Encoding Videos for the HP Touchpad</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/tech/encoding-videos-for-the-hp-touchpad/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-08-10:blog/tech/encoding-videos-for-the-hp-touchpad/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is for those who have ripped their DVDs and other video media and would like to load it onto their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; Touchpad.  I started to encode videos for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; Touchpad using HandBrake, which had given me success for video targeting my Palm Pre.   I used iPad profiles, as the display size is exactly the same.  It seemed that no matter what I tried, the files would not show up in Photos &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Videos app.  I tried quite a few options and then just gave up.  Many issues that I had with encoding video for the Touchpad seem to have been fixed with the 3.0.2 webOS update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The too long didn’t read version of this post is this: Download HandBrake, render using the iPad Preset and change frame rate to Same as Source.  Upload to Touchpad and be happy.  If you care about some of the testing I did, continue reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with a high end &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; video file, to take advantage of the full resolution of the Touchpad.  The video I played with is a BluRay version of Pixar’s Partly Cloudy.  This is a 1080p video (1920x1080), with 5.1 channel &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AC3&lt;/span&gt; sound (48 kHz and 16 bit).  This is most likely the highest video quality source that people will use for Touchpad encoding.  Runtime is 5:48 with 23.976 frame rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two pieces of software I used are Format Factory (now a dead link) and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://handbrake.fr/"&gt;Handbrake&lt;/a&gt; (Windows, Mac, Linux. Tested on the Windows version).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First render was in Format Factory with the iPad setting at 720x480 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MPEG4&lt;/span&gt;.  This rendered slightly faster than I had been seeing with HandBrake.  There is a noticeable quality loss with stretching the 720 out to the Touchpad’s 1024 width, but the video is very watchable.  If you did not have a 1024 width video to compare it to, you would not see an issue.  File Size 47.0 Mb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the same iPad setting and bumped the resolution to 1024x768, keeping all the other settings the same.  What surprised me is the file size dropped to 46.6 Mb.  Looking closer, I noticed that the video bit rate is fixed at 1000 kbs, rather than using HandBrake’s quality style setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HandBrake has a video format for the iPad at 1024 width with aspect ratio set height (but steps width down to source video width if smaller than 1024).  The only change I made before I ran this encoding was to set frame rate as Same as Source.  (It was defaulted to 29.97.)  The encoding takes longer than Format Factory (1.1-1.4x).  The file size came out to 69.8 Mb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look at both 1024 wide videos on the Touchpad, you can see the difference between Format Factory’s 1120 kbs data rate and HandBrake’s 1672 kbs data rate.  There was quite a bit of motion blocking artifacts with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FF&lt;/span&gt;’s encode.  The added time to render due to detecting quality of the frame dynamically is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I upped the Format Factory setting to use 1500 kbs video data rate (for similar to HandBrake’s total data rate) to do an apples to apples comparison.  File size came out to 67.9 Mb, so pretty close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at the two on the Touchpad, they are very hard to tell apart most of the time.  The biggest issues is with horizontal streaking on single color backgrounds for the Format Factory version.  By going with a fixed bit rate, rather than the HandBrake’s quality based setting, you also get blocking during highly changing scenes.  HandBrake will use less data during the static scenes, but more during dynamic scenes, resulting in a better encoding at the same overall file size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rendered some of the files that I have ripped from my DVDs (most 640 x proper aspect ratio height) through HandBrake, using the iPad profile.  These play great.  The Touchpad had no issues with m4v or mp4 file extension for the H.264 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MPEG&lt;/span&gt; 4 files these apps were generating. It will not display the Xvid based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MPEG4&lt;/span&gt; files that I have encoded for use with my media players and Boxee Box before H.264 was the standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching video on the Touchpad just reminds you how great the audio on this thing sounds.  Really a good video viewing experience.  Do some transcoding and enjoy your moving picture shows.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="webos"></category><category term="video encoding"></category><category term="touchpad"></category></entry><entry><title>Touchpad WiFi - Hidden Passcode Hell</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/tech/touchpad-wifi-hidden-passcode-hell/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2011-08-02:blog/tech/touchpad-wifi-hidden-passcode-hell/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have just spent the last 30 minutes trying to get our complex 64 character &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WPA&lt;/span&gt; key into my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; Touchpad so I can start the setup procedure.  The password field for the WiFi key is frustrating.
The last character is only shown for a second or two, then it too fades into the dots of obscurity.  This is fine in normal use with passwords you are used to typing, but a WiFi key is complex and entered only once per new device.
When you add to this a finiky WiFi network acceptance, you have time after time frustration.  The key is entered and network selected (even with a check mark!), but for some reason the Touchpad won’t accept anything but Cancel.
Guess who gets to type the key in again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally figured out how to view a key as I enter it and validate the key, so I can be sure the passcode part of the network acceptance is valid.  If I had done this the first time I started to enter our complex key, I would have only had to type it once and been able to verify it easily.  Typing 64 characters with only vision on the last one is a little too tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLEASE&lt;/span&gt; make an option to show the passcode.  All you have to do is change the enyo options of the text box.  Entering a passcode for WiFi should not be this hard.  If it must be secure by default, put a check box that allows “Show Passcode”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my work around:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 444px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/hp-touchpad-wifi/01-Join-Network.png" style="width: 444px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;When you have the WiFi network selection open, tap on the “+ Join Network”.  The image was captured before the Touchpad located any WiFi networks.  Normally, you will see your network and possibly others above the “+ Join Network” option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/hp-touchpad-wifi/02-Join-Network-Open.png" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;This will open a dialog that is normally used for you to enter the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSID&lt;/span&gt; of a hidden WiFi network.  Instead, we are typing our WiFi passcode in plain text (oh, glorious plain text).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/hp-touchpad-wifi/03-Type-and-Select-All.png" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;You can now see all characters and scroll back and forth to verify everything is correct (just tap and drag to the left or right.)  When it looks good, tap and hold to bring up the Select menu.  Choose Select All.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/hp-touchpad-wifi/05-Hold-for-Copy.png" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Now with everything selected, tap and hold again for the Copy menu.  Select Copy and you have your WiFi key in your clipboard.  Tap cancel and select your WiFi network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/posts/hp-touchpad-wifi/06-Hold-for-Paste.png" style="width: 443px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Tap and hold in the passcode field and you can select Paste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="touchpad"></category><category term="wifi"></category><category term="setup"></category></entry></feed>