<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>joesacher.com</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/feeds/trans-am.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.joesacher.com/</id><updated>2015-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Trans-Am Status</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/trans-am-status/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2015-07-07:blog/trans-am/trans-am-status/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the website reboot, I’m working on getting all the days of my Trans-Am trip online for the first time.
It is amazing that my tour was 13 years ago and I’m really enjoying looking back on the trip.  I’m going to try to
post at least one day journal per week.  Possibly more as I am on vacation for the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to post them with the original date, as I couldn’t find a way to post with a modern date and display the tour date without confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this post going live, I’m putting up Day 0 and Day 1.  I’ll update this post and bring back to the top as I post new updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Ride a Bicycle across the Country?</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/why-ride-a-bicycle-across-the-country/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-04:blog/trans-am/why-ride-a-bicycle-across-the-country/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been asked many times why I wanted to ride a bicycle across the county.  Having completed the trip, the question became easy to answer.  It was not as easy to answer before I left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a bicentennial baby, born in 1976.  This is the same year the Bikecentennial route was created as a celebration of our 200 years as a country.  Thousands of cyclists rode across the country on that route during the innagural year.  Many thousands more have crossed the United States on the same route since.  The route is still maintained by the same organization with a new name: Adventure Cycling.  Their maps are extremely helpful for the bicycle tourist and have kept the same basic route, with slight changes as roads are modified over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is well and good, you say, but it still doesn’t answer the why.  The truth is that I didn’t really know.  I read a tour report on-line and thought it sounded interesting.  Over the years it fermented into a strong desire.  I wondered if this was something I could do.  I started riding a Trek 520 touring bike in college.  I was overweight.  No nicer way to say it.  Riding 50 miles in a day was a task.  This wasn’t because I couldn’t physically do it, my butt just couldn’t handle the time on the bike.  Yes, I had the real bike shorts.  I tried three different seats.  It just didn’t work.  All season would be required before I could do two back to back 50 mile days.  I couldn’t see myself riding across the country, when you are doing 50+ mile days, every day.  The idea was put on the shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started working at Office Depot as a Business Machine Specialist, while in High School.  Lower hours during the school year and full weeks during the summer, I didn’t have much time off.  When High School turned to college, I worked as much as I could to help pay for school.  Added to that a challenging Engineering curriculum and there wasn’t much time off.  Then I started work at a consulting company, pulling crazy hours and throwing myself into my work.  The reality was that I needed to get a life, but I didn’t realize it at the time.  I had work and not much else.  Work was challenging and I enjoyed it, but I was burning myself out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2001, I ran into a man on a recumbent bicycle.  The man’s name was Pete, something I didn’t know until months later when we became friends.  I asked him so many questions that he graciously answered.  Soon after that encounter, I purchased my first recumbent.  It would be the first of many to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With recumbents came pain free riding.  They allow you to ride a bicycle, while you sit in a lazy boy recliner.  I started easily riding 50 miles.  I rode a century (100 miles) without much problem.  I thought back to the first century I rode on an old mountain bike without road tires.  That experience is currently in Webster’s as a definition for pain.  I had trouble walking for a day or two after that.  With the recumbent century, I just had sore legs and nothing else hurt.  This was the way to ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now having a way to ride across the country, I began to seriously consider it.  I didn’t know if I could actually make it all the way across, physically.  That became another reason to do it, just to see if I could.  This is the same reason people have climbed mountains and explored new realms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the discovery of recumbents was occurring, I started consulting for an Internet startup in my day job.  Working 6 and 7 days a week for 80+ hours each week can take a toll.  It was challenging and I enjoyed the work, but I was getting further burned out.  I needed a vacation that I didn’t feel like I’d had since High School.  I saved up so much vacation time, it was ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally set a date for the trip and told my boss that I would need 4 months off work.  I told him that I would like to come back to work, but would take the time off regardless of a job waiting for me or not.  I had over a month of vacation to use and knew I would get a few more paychecks during the trip, even if I was forced to quit.  If I needed to find a new job when I got back, so be it.  I wound up with two months paid leave (I could pull forward vacation time from the new &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PTO&lt;/span&gt; system in addition to my vacation) and two months without pay.  Then I would return to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would be bored with a description of all the small projects I was put on during the months before my departure.  I couldn’t do a full term project, because I wouldn’t be around.  As never happens (snicker), all the projects ran long.  Instead of getting ready for the trip, I was working serious overtime again.  I was getting burned out with a vengeance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did I go?  Had I known the serious and life changing effect this trip would have on me, I would have come up with a better answer.  But the only answer I came up with is this: I had to go.  I needed those hours of uninterrupted thought.  I needed to figure out if I was doing what I wanted in life.  I needed to change something.  I needed to see if I could ride a bicycle across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just had to go.  So I went.  And it changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My outlook on so many things is different.  The definition of what you actually need to live.  We think we need so much more than we do.  When life is a bicycle and what you can carry, you have to simplify and ration your belongings.  Each hill demands justification for every pound on the bike.  For all but the most seasoned bicycle tourists, the first few towns’ post office is a must stop location.  You have been on tour for some days and you can’t for the life of you understand why you brought this heavy, useless [fill in the blank].  Then be prepared to do the same thing in another few days, when yet another piece of equipment is voted off of the bicycle.  This is an event similar to backpackers, where common hostels and other meeting locations often have a place to leave things that others can take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t a month that goes by that I don’t long to be out on the road again for a while.  I am now over 5 years from my big trip and I still miss it.  The challenge was almost too much for me at first.  But it was an emotional triumph to persevere and conquer my weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience isn’t the same for everyone.  Many on the tour would have only goals in mind.  Finishing the tour in a certain amont of time.  This is often a necessity due to work schedules and other things.  I didn’t finish the trip, due to an accident.  But it didn’t matter, as my goal was touring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised when I would ask if others had seen the beautiful artesian well or stopped at the museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;Nope.  But we made our mileage in under 5 hours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who cares?  How full of experiences were those miles?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same is true with life.  Are you living life to really live it or are to constantly striving &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONLY&lt;/span&gt; towards goals and missing life?  Is your job and crazy hours caused by the things you surround yourself with and who know rule you?  Life can be as simple as a bicycle and being homeless.  Everything else is gravy.  But too much else is a millstone around your neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with a purpose and justify all the drains in your life.  Live simply.  Live happy.  Because doing otherwise isn’t really living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that by riding a bicycle across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 1 - Yorktown to Jamestown, VA</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-20:blog/trans-am/day-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3710-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3710-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Dave Knight (left) and my dad (right) about to pilot the Baron from Bowman Field in Louisville, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KY&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle tourist is greeted with two choices when starting their tour.  Do I ride away from my home or pack up everything and take alternate transportation to the start?  For local tours, the loop method is a good idea.  Start off in one direction and ride in a big loop until you end up back home.  If I had a year’s time, not just a couple months, I would enjoy a loop tour of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;.  It would be ideal to leave Indiana, riding in the northern states during the warmer months and the southern states during the cooler months.  Unfortunately, I didn’t have the few extra weeks it would take to get to Virginia.  My dad has some good flying friends with access to a large enough plane to get us out to the start..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3717-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3717-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A cruising altitude in the Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave is a part owner of a Baron twin engine aircraft with enough space for me, my father, Dave, and my gear.  Dad and I arrived at Bowman Field in Louisville, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KY&lt;/span&gt; around noon.  We loaded up the plane as soon as Dave arrived.  The local Air Traffic Controllers allowed us to depart a little past 1 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day had a dreary cast, under a solid fluffy blanket of clouds.  An occasional mist hit the windshield and we sampled small rain showers, on the climb to our cruising altitude.  Due to icing at our intended altitude of 11,000 feet, Dave asked for and was cleared up to 13,000 feet.  The Baron is not a pressurized cabin, so air pressure inside is the same as the air pressure outside.  This requires oxygen for the pilot, above 10,000 feet.  Oxygen is required for other members of the plane for altitudes above 14,000 feet for short times and lower altitudes for longer durations.  There were only two sets of oxygen, so Dad and I switched off.  I went more without than with, because Dad wanted to do some of the flying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gave me a chance to practice a pressure breathing technique I had read about for those entering high altitude environments without supplemental oxygen.  The problem isn’t with the percentage of oxygen in the air at higher altitudes; it is a problem with the pressure of the air in your lungs.  The lower pressure means less total volume of air, and therefore less total volume of oxygen.  The low pressure also doesn’t help with pressing the oxygen molecules into your blood stream via your lungs.  The pressure of air in your lungs can be increased by forcing your lips together, while your diaphragm muscles force the air out.  This technique would later prove beneficial when climbing over Hoosier Pass in the Rocky Mountains.  It helped things somewhat, but I was always ready for the oxygen when it was offered.  There were a few times that I became slightly woozy, with just the very beginning stages of hypoxia.  It was an interesting experience, which gave me a headache that would last the rest of the day.  My slight dehydration was also a co-conspiritor in my cranial crankiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience of flying over mountains I would soon see again was somewhat surreal.  The entire trip out took around 2 hours by plane.  The trip back to passing within 50 miles of home would take almost a month by bicycle.  Just when we descended through the cloud layer and opened up many photo worth scenes, I realized my spare batteries were packed out of reach in the back.  My camera went dead as Newport News Airport came within view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3719-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3719-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Unloading the plane at the Newport News Airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shot am most annoyed for missing was the giant aircraft carrier.  It was a beautiful view and seemed bigger than the grass strip in Scottsburg, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IN&lt;/span&gt;, where dad taught me how to land our Aeronica Champ.  An F-18 is quite a different animal, with a stall speed nearly 5 times that number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed at the Newport New Airport just after 3 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;.  After taxing to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FBO&lt;/span&gt; (Fixed Base Operator, the “gas station” of an airport), we began unloading my bike and gear.  It took a few minutes to reassemble everything and get ready to ride over to the start.  Instead of doing that, one of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FBO&lt;/span&gt; employees was nice enough to give me a ride to the Yorktown Visitor’s Center.  So I loaded the bike into a van and went for a quick 9 mile ride.  By the end of the day, I was really happy that I didn’t need to spend almost an hour doing this ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3720-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3720-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bike loaded and ready to tour, with one exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a second time assembling and loading the bike, then checking over everything, I was off to find the Victory Monument (official start of the Trans-American trail).  I stopped 100 feet later.  I couldn’t get my bike computer to work.  I hoped the sensor just got bumped away from the magnet on the spoke.  Any experienced cyclist has run into that one a few times.  I moved the magnet until it made a slight “whack” sound on the sensor, then backed away every so slightly.  But I still had no speed indicated, so that wasn’t the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remembered having to unwind the handlebars after we set the bike down out of the van.  Sure enough, the computer wires were ripped raggedly apart.  I’ll be in need of my first repair sooner than expected.  Anyone know where I can borrow a soldering iron, a little wire, and some heat shrink?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3721-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3721-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Timer based shot at the Victory Monument, with camera sitting on the ground due to unreliable “helpers”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3732-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3732-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Top of the Victory Monument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took some pictures at the Monument before heading for Williamsburg.  I attempted to get another tourist to take a picture of me, but could not locate anything when I reviewed the screen after they left.  I set it all up and they just needed to press the button.  I immediately saw the advantages of bringing a digital camera.  Had I been shooting film, I would have assumed the picture of my overweight self would have already been taken at the monument.  I learned how to use the self timer for the first time and a few seconds later I had the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3722-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3722-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 223px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3723-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3723-m.jpg" style="width: 223px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 212px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3724-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3724-m.jpg" style="width: 212px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3727-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3727-m.jpg" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3729-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3729-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 231px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3726-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3726-m.jpg" style="width: 231px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 197px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3728-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3728-m.jpg" style="width: 197px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3730-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3730-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3735-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3735-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Ceremonial dipping of the tire in the… man this bike is heavy, nevermind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just past the Victory Monument, there is a road that doesn’t allow motor vehicles.  I found the first benefit of bicycle touring.  I rode along the 7 houses built over 200 years ago, when Yorktown was Virginia’s leading seaport.  Cannon fire damaged many of the buliding during the Seige of Yorktown, the last major land battle of the Revolutionary War, which ended on October 19, 1781.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3736-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3736-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;George Washington Memorial Highway (Hwy 17) crossing over the York River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After riders start at the Victory Monument, it is ceremonial to dip your back wheel in the York River as the Atlantic Ocean representative body of water.  I thought about that.  I tried to lift my bike.  I thought about carrying my bike over the sand and back.  Then I considered unloading it and making that slightly easier.  Then I just took another picture from a different angle and called it good.  I probably would have done it, if I had more time in the day.  But time was moving, so I needed to as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3740-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3740-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Entering Colonial Parkway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonists named this river first Charles and then York, both as an honor to the Duke of York.  It was known to the Indians of the region as Pamunkey, a name still used by a smaller tributary of the York River today.  While only 26 miles in length, the tidal waters of the York River flow over the deepest natural channel of any Chesapeake Bay tributary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3741-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3741-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mileage signs come so much slower than in a car, so I got excited each time I saw one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the York River is the site of Werowocomoco, an Indian village that was Powhatan’s “chiefest habitation” in the early period of the Jamestown settlement.  This was the location that John Smith was held prisoner in 1607.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride was really beautiful, but there were so many things to see that I needed to ride right past.  It was after 4 o’clock, with only 4 hours of sunlight left, and I had no clue where I was going to stay tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3745-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3745-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would learn that it is often easier to find places to stay in less congested areas (other than motels and hotels).  In the big cities, cars are king.  So was it most places here.  I pulled into the Williamsburg Visitor’s Center around 6:30, as everything was closing down.  I received pointers to the lower priced hotels in the area and where the restaurants were hiding.  My lunch wasn’t large before I left Jeffersonville and I was famished.  I found a Golden Corral.  There is a reason why there are few “All You Can Eat” buffets along the Trans-Am trail.  A cyclist can burn thousands of extra calories a day.  And buffets can go out of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3751-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3751-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restaurant was breathing tourists in and out as I ate and read about the route ahead.  They all seemed to be taking their first gasps of vacation, after the school year finished.  As long as the food doesn’t run out, the best you can hope for is a busy buffet.  Food turned over faster, tastes better.  Hunger also has that effect on food.  While I enjoyed resting, reading, and people watching, I knew daylight was fading.  My choices were hotel or not.  The hotels were right here.  If I stayed in a hotel or motel, I could ride back into Williamsburg for a visit tomorrow.  But this is a bicycle tour, not a tourist trip.  I wanted to be some miles under my belt and away from all the people and traffic, so off I rode into the fading daylight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3752-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3752-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left the restaurant a little after 8 towards Jamestown.  This was the best option I could come up with for the night.  Soon the darkness pushed back the day and stopped to rig for night riding.  I turned on my rear lights and flipped the switch on my “dashboard” to enable the headlight.  I knew these were going to be needed through out the trip, but didn’t think I’d be riding into the night during the first day out.  I finally pulled into the campground after 9 and was greeted with a $22 campsite!  That is quite a bit of dough for a plot of grass and the use of a shower and bathroom.  Supply and demand was in full force in Jamestown.  While I knew $22 wasn’t the most I would spend for a night, as I planned a few motel stays, I hoped it was the most I would ever spend for a campsite.  Oh well, where else am I gonna go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3754-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3754-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Faking sleep to take a picture on my outfit for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my tent pitched and shower taken, I fired up my little Libretto laptop and started typing up today’s journal entry.  This little laptop is about the size of a Disney packaged &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; movie.  The keyboard is smaller than normal and I had not yet adjusted to it.  The headache still hung around as I typed up my day’s journal, so I constantly sipped on water.  The color of my urine had assured me that I was still dehydrated or someone slipped a bunch of vitamin B into my food at the Golden Corral.  I assumed the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night was unseasonably cold.  Temperatures dropped to 34 over night.  My 20 degree mummy bag felt nice over the small Thermarest air mattress.  The full hood was too warm, but a small fleece cap was just right.  With my water bottles available for sipping a few times through out the night, I slept well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 0 - Final Shakedown Ride</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-0/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-19:blog/trans-am/day-0/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-0/3659-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-0/3659-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I completely loaded up my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RANS&lt;/span&gt; Rocket.  I’ve built many custom components to make it into a cross-country touring machine.  Unfortunately, I haven’t had as much time getting ready for the trip as I wanted.  Work pressed into taking far too much of my time, so both equipment and physical shape preparation was lacking.  I will just have to get in shape by doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-0/3660-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-0/3660-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this lack of preparation chewed up almost two weeks of my time off.  I spent a week getting my belongings into storage and moved out of my apartment.  I spent another week finishing equipment builds and other touring builds.  I also finished up the code for my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; based email journal and mailing list.  It may be hard to connect over the analog modem through my Star-Tac cell phone, even just to send updates.  So, hopefully I won’t be having to fix code while on the road.  I can currently compose updates as an email to a certain address, which will post and distribute them when the email is sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-0/3664-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-0/3664-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I will be flying out to Newport News Airport and making my way to the start of this adventure.  After more than two years of planning, it is really nice to get this started.  Hopefully I will think the same thing a week or two into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time for a good nights sleep.  My last in a bed for a little while at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll see you on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="touring"></category><category term="travelogue"></category></entry></feed>