<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>joesacher.com</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/feeds/trans-am.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.joesacher.com/</id><updated>2015-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Trans-Am Status</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/trans-am-status/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2015-07-11:blog/trans-am/trans-am-status/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just added Days 4 and 5 travel journal entries.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Ride a Bicycle across the Country?</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/why-ride-a-bicycle-across-the-country/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2007-12-04:blog/trans-am/why-ride-a-bicycle-across-the-country/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been asked many times why I wanted to ride a bicycle across the county.  Having completed the trip, the question became easy to answer.  It was not as easy to answer before I left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a bicentennial baby, born in 1976.  This is the same year the Bikecentennial route was created as a celebration of our 200 years as a country.  Thousands of cyclists rode across the country on that route during the innagural year.  Many thousands more have crossed the United States on the same route since.  The route is still maintained by the same organization with a new name: Adventure Cycling.  Their maps are extremely helpful for the bicycle tourist and have kept the same basic route, with slight changes as roads are modified over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is well and good, you say, but it still doesn’t answer the why.  The truth is that I didn’t really know.  I read a tour report on-line and thought it sounded interesting.  Over the years it fermented into a strong desire.  I wondered if this was something I could do.  I started riding a Trek 520 touring bike in college.  I was overweight.  No nicer way to say it.  Riding 50 miles in a day was a task.  This wasn’t because I couldn’t physically do it, my butt just couldn’t handle the time on the bike.  Yes, I had the real bike shorts.  I tried three different seats.  It just didn’t work.  All season would be required before I could do two back to back 50 mile days.  I couldn’t see myself riding across the country, when you are doing 50+ mile days, every day.  The idea was put on the shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started working at Office Depot as a Business Machine Specialist, while in High School.  Lower hours during the school year and full weeks during the summer, I didn’t have much time off.  When High School turned to college, I worked as much as I could to help pay for school.  Added to that a challenging Engineering curriculum and there wasn’t much time off.  Then I started work at a consulting company, pulling crazy hours and throwing myself into my work.  The reality was that I needed to get a life, but I didn’t realize it at the time.  I had work and not much else.  Work was challenging and I enjoyed it, but I was burning myself out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2001, I ran into a man on a recumbent bicycle.  The man’s name was Pete, something I didn’t know until months later when we became friends.  I asked him so many questions that he graciously answered.  Soon after that encounter, I purchased my first recumbent.  It would be the first of many to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With recumbents came pain free riding.  They allow you to ride a bicycle, while you sit in a lazy boy recliner.  I started easily riding 50 miles.  I rode a century (100 miles) without much problem.  I thought back to the first century I rode on an old mountain bike without road tires.  That experience is currently in Webster’s as a definition for pain.  I had trouble walking for a day or two after that.  With the recumbent century, I just had sore legs and nothing else hurt.  This was the way to ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now having a way to ride across the country, I began to seriously consider it.  I didn’t know if I could actually make it all the way across, physically.  That became another reason to do it, just to see if I could.  This is the same reason people have climbed mountains and explored new realms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the discovery of recumbents was occurring, I started consulting for an Internet startup in my day job.  Working 6 and 7 days a week for 80+ hours each week can take a toll.  It was challenging and I enjoyed the work, but I was getting further burned out.  I needed a vacation that I didn’t feel like I’d had since High School.  I saved up so much vacation time, it was ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally set a date for the trip and told my boss that I would need 4 months off work.  I told him that I would like to come back to work, but would take the time off regardless of a job waiting for me or not.  I had over a month of vacation to use and knew I would get a few more paychecks during the trip, even if I was forced to quit.  If I needed to find a new job when I got back, so be it.  I wound up with two months paid leave (I could pull forward vacation time from the new &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PTO&lt;/span&gt; system in addition to my vacation) and two months without pay.  Then I would return to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would be bored with a description of all the small projects I was put on during the months before my departure.  I couldn’t do a full term project, because I wouldn’t be around.  As never happens (snicker), all the projects ran long.  Instead of getting ready for the trip, I was working serious overtime again.  I was getting burned out with a vengeance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did I go?  Had I known the serious and life changing effect this trip would have on me, I would have come up with a better answer.  But the only answer I came up with is this: I had to go.  I needed those hours of uninterrupted thought.  I needed to figure out if I was doing what I wanted in life.  I needed to change something.  I needed to see if I could ride a bicycle across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just had to go.  So I went.  And it changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My outlook on so many things is different.  The definition of what you actually need to live.  We think we need so much more than we do.  When life is a bicycle and what you can carry, you have to simplify and ration your belongings.  Each hill demands justification for every pound on the bike.  For all but the most seasoned bicycle tourists, the first few towns’ post office is a must stop location.  You have been on tour for some days and you can’t for the life of you understand why you brought this heavy, useless [fill in the blank].  Then be prepared to do the same thing in another few days, when yet another piece of equipment is voted off of the bicycle.  This is an event similar to backpackers, where common hostels and other meeting locations often have a place to leave things that others can take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t a month that goes by that I don’t long to be out on the road again for a while.  I am now over 5 years from my big trip and I still miss it.  The challenge was almost too much for me at first.  But it was an emotional triumph to persevere and conquer my weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience isn’t the same for everyone.  Many on the tour would have only goals in mind.  Finishing the tour in a certain amont of time.  This is often a necessity due to work schedules and other things.  I didn’t finish the trip, due to an accident.  But it didn’t matter, as my goal was touring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised when I would ask if others had seen the beautiful artesian well or stopped at the museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;Nope.  But we made our mileage in under 5 hours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who cares?  How full of experiences were those miles?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same is true with life.  Are you living life to really live it or are to constantly striving &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONLY&lt;/span&gt; towards goals and missing life?  Is your job and crazy hours caused by the things you surround yourself with and who know rule you?  Life can be as simple as a bicycle and being homeless.  Everything else is gravy.  But too much else is a millstone around your neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live with a purpose and justify all the drains in your life.  Live simply.  Live happy.  Because doing otherwise isn’t really living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that by riding a bicycle across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 5 - Lake Anna to Palmyra, VA</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-5/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-24:blog/trans-am/day-5/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4140-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4140-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Dawn quietly cracking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up just before dawn cracked at 5:45.  I had packed up everything but my sleeping gear before I went to bed, because I wanted to secure as much of it as I could from any animal or other visitors.  I was out of the campground before 6.  I still couldn’t find anyone to check in with, so I dropped off a couple singles in the slot near the closed sign, which I felt was far more than the accommodations were worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4141-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4141-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Delicious hot breakfast sandwiches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The country store just out of the campground had hot biscuit sandwiches.  I enjoyed a country ham, egg, and cheese biscuit as I hoped for the temperature to rise.  It did not, so I geared up for the downhills in 40 degree wind and started peddaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4142-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4142-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Entering Mineral, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VA&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 10 miles of riding with about 250 feet climbing, I entered Mineral, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VA&lt;/span&gt;.  This country is really pretty to ride through.  I stopped to peal off a layer for the rising temperature and enjoy the sights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4144-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4144-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The Trevilians School House (1880-1924)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found an interesting site just as I was leaving Mineral, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VA&lt;/span&gt;: The Trevilians School House.  It is a single room building, about 20 feet on each side, setup inside with period desks and such.  Sambo Johnson owned both the property of the original location and where it now sits in Mineral. It is believed his mother or Aunt taught there and he moved and restored the school several years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it was locked, the front steps were perfect and shaded from the sun which had now warmed up the day.  I sat down to type up a little of my ride journal, then I put on some sunscreen and got back on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4145-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4145-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 65px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4146-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4146-m.jpg" style="width: 65px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4147-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4147-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4149-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4149-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4151-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4151-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4152-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4152-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lunch time at Johnny’s Quik Stop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4153-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4153-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped in Pendleton, the town 1 mile out of Mineral.  There the gas station/mart had some newly prepared chicken fingers and potato wedges.  I decided to partake in some of those and wasn’t disappointed.  I talked with a few locals and one guy who lived on the route later in Kents Store, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VA&lt;/span&gt;.  He gave me a lay of the land and told me that I would be doing good to get to Palmyra today.  It was only 10 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; and I already had 15 or so miles under my belt, so I wasn’t worried.  But boy did those hills start coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4154-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4154-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t much to talk about today, I just road through some pretty countryside and climbed a bunch.  Today was the first day I was able to see the landscape actually rolling, and I am definitely about to hit the real climbs soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pulled into the single store in Kents Store.  (One wonders if this town was formed by Kent, who had a store.  Hmm, I guess we’ll call it Kent’s Store.)  I loved the air-conditioning.   My thermometer was indicating 85-88 in the shaded grass and 92-98 on the sunlit road.  Needless to say, I stayed in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt; for a while.  The ice cream sandwich and cold Gatorade helped to lower my core temperature.  When I went to the toilet, there was even a comics section from today.  That was a nice diversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4155-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4155-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Old Stone Jail Sign in Palmyra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was visiting with people at the store, a man came by asking about the bike.  He understood everything until I got to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;What’s that?” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I explain about satellites and positioning and show him the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;That’s what I need on my boat!”.  Apparently he has gotten lost a time or too, and I agreed that it would be perfect.  So I told him where to pick them up and gave him a few brands to check for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4156-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4156-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Old Stone Jail in Palmyra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the people of Virginia have been really great.  My left arm gets a little sore from returning all the waves I’m getting.  But I do have two things to bring up about Virginia road signs.  One is a gripe and one is a compliment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4157-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4157-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Monument for Confederate Soldiers of Fluvanna County&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the gripe:  What is up with numbering every road and then also giving it a name.  I’ll ask someone about a road and they say, “There ain’t no 634 around here, you want to take Something Something Road.”  Turns out that they are one and the same.  This happens occasionally everywhere, but it seems like &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVERY&lt;/span&gt; small road has this happening in Virginia. Strange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4167-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4167-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Young girl fishing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the compliment: Any road that dead end within a mile or so has a sign at the turn off to is “Road Ends 0.5 Miles” or whatever the value it needs.  This is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GREAT&lt;/span&gt;.  I have been touring around Indiana and you assume some country road (say 400E or similar) keeps going over a stream or through a forested area, until you ride a mile and it dead ends.  The best that you get is a “Dead End” sign after the last turnoff (maybe .9 miles in).  Kudos to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VDOT&lt;/span&gt; for these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pulled into Palmyra around 3:30.  I was totally spent.  The Old Stone Jail Museum was interesting, but unfortunately closed.  The hours didn’t really meet with my current situation, so I rode on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4165-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4165-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Father and daughter fishing from the shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped at the cafe right at the turn onto 53.  This is the same cafe that I have read of other TransAm cyclists camping behind.  I had a milkshake, purely for medicinal purposes.  (You know, that whole core temperature lowering thing.)  I washed the shake down with a burger, wedges and cole slaw.  Then I sat inside the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt; and looked at my options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4166-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4166-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Hwy 15 bridge over Rivanna River&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a 20+ miles ride, part on route and part off, over to Charlottesville’s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KOA&lt;/span&gt;.  This would then require more off route riding back.  Or I could ride more than that into Charlottesville and get a motel.  I want a rest day tomorrow, but I didn’t think I can hit either of those with my legs where they are at right then.  So, I killed time in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt; and then went to setup camp behind the store.  By killed time, I tried to debug why some email messages are not going out and wrote up travel journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4168-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4168-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4158-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4158-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My illegal campsite near the boat launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is actually a boat launch for the Rivanna River.  I noticed the sign after I setup camp that says only fishing and boat launching, no camping, alcoholic beverages, with penalty of arrest.  Oh, well.  I ain’t pedaling anywhere else today.   Hopefully no ranger comes by to take me to jail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4171-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4171-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Sign indicating that I could be arrested tonight.  Lets hope not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m beginning to wish my tent was closer to dark green rather that bright white.  I’ve got the fly off and the windows open, so all you see is a white border.  We will see what happens.  I’d like to get up and out of here by 6:30, so I can ride straight into Charlottesville via 53 with the hopefully lesser Saturday morning traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-5/4172-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-5/4172-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The sunset was beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memorial Day weekend is making me second guess a bunch of things.  This is my first night in a half open sky for star gazing, and I fell asleep looking at stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I am 167 miles along the Trans-Am trail and I have ridden just under 200 miles.  Those side trips add up, I guess.  Due to the rounding of corners by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, this is probably just a little under actual travel distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is brought to you by the letters C and H and by the number 9 and 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C is for Climbing, 2000 feet today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H is for heat, I met along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 is a number when multiplied by ten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then added to 5 is the temperature I’m in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, now we know why I’m a bicycle tourist and not a poet.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 4 - Ashland to Lake Anna, VA</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-4/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-23:blog/trans-am/day-4/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4051-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4051-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My view while sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4052-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4052-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My tent’s view of me the last two nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before willing myself out of my warm sleeping bag, I snapped a picture of my view. I rose into the cold and decided on a cold breakfast to keep with the theme.  I finished off my first pack of Fig Newtons and had a mug of Gatorade (my morning drink of choice for that last few days.) The early Gatorade seems to give my muscles what they need to start out.  I knew I would be having an early lunch, as I planned to go into Ashland today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4053-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4053-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The Petes getting ready to ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a kick out of the simple parts of bicycle touring that the Pete’s and I shared.  Cycling clothes that we washed last night while we showered, hanging out to dry.  They may have used the on site laundry, I just didn’t have enough to justify it.   A little time in the shower with some soap works just as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4054-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4054-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Packing up and eating my breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out of the campground, hit the restroom, and did my bike pocket check.  You know how you do the pocket slap for your keys and wallet?   I do the same for my essentials on the bike after every stop.  My water bottle slap came up empty.   Megan Pete was holding them out as I rode a few feet back to camp.   I made sure that they knew the short cut to get back on route which I had, through much effort, learned last night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4057-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4057-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lunchtime for today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I detoured off the route in Ashland to find a Radio Shack and a Post Office.  On the way I stopped at a Jersey Mike’s Subs and got a Giant Club Supreme.  They didn’t miss use the word giant!  In the picture of it, the two paper plates it is spanning are normal large sized plates.  I had them wrap up that last 1/4 to take with me.  That made my little breakfast work out perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4060-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4060-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Those are full sized paper plates.  This is a big sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4063-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4063-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Solar charging works after getting fuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was successful on finding both a Radio Shack and the Post Office.  I purchased a 5 pack of spare fuses for the 12V battery.  By the end of the day, my battery had charged fine via the solar cell.  They didn’t have a loaner soldering iron and I figured that I could find a better solution than buying $30 worth of stuff to fix my bike computer wire, then immediately mailing it to my parents.  I’ll be using the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; as my only bike computer for a little while longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4064-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4064-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Time to drop some weight at the post office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode up to the Post Office and started pulling out bags.  The time honored tradition of elimination was upon me.  I draped the laundry from yesterday that was still wet all over my bike.  I went through every piece of equipment that I had on the bike and made each piece justify itself to me.  I came up with about 8 pounds of stuff that I could live without.  It should be in my parents house day after tomorrow, thanks to the fine people of the United States Postal Service.  With that done, I headed out of town around 1:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4066-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4066-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Dual railroad tracks running up center of Ashland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashland has some history in railroad, as do many towns in this nation.  Two main lines run right through town and made for some pretty scenes.  The railroad depot was a nice place to sit on a bench and read a book.  But alas, there are miles to go before I sleep and I had yet to purchase a book.  Most of the book I brought are in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; format and located on CDs.  Although, there has been enough to do that I haven’t yet pulled them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4067-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4067-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Ashland train station&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Blunt’s Bridge Road, I started hitting my first serious hills of the trip.  Before, I had not been steep enough to keep me from winching myself up with little effort.  This one was more like something from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hillyhundred.org/"&gt;Hilly Hundred in Bloomington&lt;/a&gt;, except I don’t have all this gear on my bike for the hilly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4068-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4068-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Not sure what bicycle route 1 is, but it might be closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was struggling up this hill, I saw an older lady in front of me doing the same thing on foot.  When I got to the top, I pulled over to get my heart back in my chest and chatted for a little bit.  She told me that if she climbs that hill a few times a week, it just might get her some vigor back.  Well her body and stamina was looking a lot younger that the years on her face, so I say kudos to you.  I know a few people who need that kind of mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4080-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4080-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Church Quarter log house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4078-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4078-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed an old log cabin and pulled the bike over to check it out.  At first I thought it might be someone’s home, but then read the plaque.  It is one of the few surviving cabins with a certain style of construction.  I took pictures all around and looked at the various construction details.  Instead of flats, they used notches to lock in the logs.  The door jam height was extremely low, by modern standards.  I would bang my head a few times going in and out of this place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a water tap and it was pressurized.  I assume it is city water, as I heard no pump start up.  I let it run a little as I soaked my head and shirt, and filled up bottles before heading out again.  That was a great way to escape the heat that started building today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4081-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4081-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4082-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4082-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4084-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4084-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4085-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4085-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4086-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4086-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4087-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4087-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4088-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4088-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4089-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4089-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4090-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4090-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4091-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4091-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 82px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4092-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4092-m.jpg" style="width: 82px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4098-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4098-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4077-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4077-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed on the route to Scotchtown (which is a couple miles longer than you would have to go on 738) and wasn’t too happy with the results.  I climbed many, many hills and when I finally got to Scotchtown, I would have to ride a steep 1/2 mile downhill to get there.  Sorry Patrick Henry, I know its your home and everything, but I’m not ready to optionally climb another hill that steep to see the house and 18 century antiques.  There are too many hills to climb today and not enough hours to do it.  I seen too many tourist places already and want some simple bike touring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4100-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4100-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My map clip and south slanted solar cell holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4101-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4101-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My “dashboard” view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I snapped a few photos of my “dashboard view” with the map and solar cell.  I also took a blurry shot of my air horn, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, computer, headlight switches, and Halt dog spray.  I stopped to take a look at the Fork Church historical marker and the current church building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 74px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4093-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4093-m.jpg" style="width: 74px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4094-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4094-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4095-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4095-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4096-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4096-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4103-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4103-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4108-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4108-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4110-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4110-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a break at a little store in Coatesville.  I enjoyed some pecan spins and a Gatorade Ice.  It is kind of fun stopping at one of these little hole in the wall stores.  You never know what is available and it is always a little adventure.  The shade of the large tree was perfect for a pit stop.  I don’t mind standing for a break, because I get to sit while riding on the recumbent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4111-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4111-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4112-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4112-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took the time to notice my many burns from mishandling the cook stove.  I have the best burn on my thumb and a minor little one on my arm.  As I got more skilled at camp cooking, these became less frequent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4114-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4114-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Check out the teeth on this beaver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4105-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4105-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;After a hard hill, buying this car sounded good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just after leaving the store, I ran into more road kill.  Check out the teeth on this one.  As I was snapping this photo, some people stopped an asked what I was doing.  I just said, “taking a picture of road kill, the first one I’ve ever gotten with a bike.”  They just looked at me strange and drove off.  What?  I thought it was funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of a difficult hill, I saw a car for sale.  As I crawled past it, finishing the hill, I thought that the price seemed reasonable.  But a Taurus isn’t comfortable for me and I didn’t think my bike would fit in the back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4116-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4116-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bumpass Post Office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4115-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4115-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many hills later, I road through Bumpass.  I’m not sure what syllables to accentuate either, but it really gave me a chuckle.  I’m guessing it is either a place where bums come to get across the mountains or a place where the road is bumpy and they want to warn you.  I didn’t really see either to determine the correct pronunciation.  I couldn’t find any locals to ask either, and I’m guessing they have heard it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4121-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4121-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The edge of Lake Anna&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4117-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4117-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Shadow touring self-portrait&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past Buckner, I reached Lake Anna.  This area has really reminded me of Lake Cumberland in Kentucky.  The little country stores, the lovely farm views, and what else…  Oh yeah, never a flat road for miles.  You are either going up or down.  My leg muscles are going to need a day off soon or they are going on strike.  I stopped at a large store for the area.  After walking past the bait displays, I purchased some food for the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4124-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4124-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Cooking dinner for the night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4126-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4126-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;View up into the tree canopy over my “campsite”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got into the Lake Anna Family Campground after &lt;span class="caps"&gt;8PM&lt;/span&gt;.  What a joke.   I’m sure it was in better condition when Donna wrote her book.  I got there too late to check in, I guess.  I wandered around for a for a while on the bike and saw no place where I would check in.  I just dropped my Thermarest on a picnic table at what I thought to be a site and threw my sleeping bag over it.  Well, that is after I cleaned off the inch of pine needles and leaves that were residing on the table.  It looked like this place hasn’t been used this year.  It might actually be closed, but it looks like there are a few permanent residents in the little shack cabins and RVs scattered around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4127-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4127-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Outside of the rest room and showers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4133-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4133-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Shower had water and was hot.  Good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After cooking up some dinner, I walked up to the bath house to take care of business and get a shower.  Seeing the toilets made me laugh.  For some reason I thought of Goldilocks and the Three Bears.  One toilet with a plunger, one toilet without a seat, one toilet that was just right.  Well, not just right.  More like, do you business quickly and just in the shower to make sure you don’t catch anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shower was nice and hot and felt good after a day of riding.  I gave my clothes from today a scrub, finally starting to get into what felt like a rhythm as a bicycle tourist.  I filled up some water bottles and decided to brush my teeth at camp.  I wanted another snack before bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4129-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4129-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4130-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4130-m.jpg" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4131-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4131-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4132-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4132-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4134-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4134-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-4/4139-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-4/4139-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My bed for the night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was anticipating mosquitoes to be a problem, but I didn’t use any spray.   As I watched the moon rise behind the beautiful foliage, only 3 mosquitoes came to visit me.  Those 3 are no longer with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew the huge canopy of leaves would make dew not a problem, but it restricted my view of the stars.  I guess there are always trade offs.   I was surprised how much I enjoyed falling asleep, to the sounds of nature, in this little decrepit “Family Campground.”&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 3 - Glendale to near Ashland, VA</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-3/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-22:blog/trans-am/day-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3957-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3957-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Willis Church Campsite in the Morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t get a chance to finish typing up my journal and answer emails before bed yesterday.  While eating and writing, the temperature dove off a cliff.  The food from my cook stove was warming for a while, but with the food and hot tea gone, night’s chill started winning the battle.  Last night was cooler than my first night on tour.  Not being near a big city might have been a factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3961-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3961-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Willis Church Building&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first night I used my full mummy bag.  I’m talking near freezing, mummy bag pulled tight so only your mouth and nose is out kind of cold.  That mummy bag was perfect.  I woke up and didn’t want to get up.  Unfortunately my bladder has a veto over what I want, so I stepped out into the cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3966-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3966-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Tent and Dogs warming in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun had my tent up to around 65 degrees, so I didn’t expect the 40 degree air.  I started breakfast and began slowly breaking camp.  I listened to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPR&lt;/span&gt; again and played with the dogs that came by.  One belongs to Pastor Harrell and the other is the neighbor’s.  Just for the record, the neighbor’s dog is all interested in the process of me eating oatmeal and raisins, but he doesn’t care for the stuff himself.  Guess it needs some bullion cubes or something else meat flavored to get him interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3967-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3967-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Pastor Harrell visiting in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started looking into all the shifting problems I had yesterday.  It turns out to be a combination of factors.  Most notably, is the fact than my cassette has worked loose. I’m not sure how exactly that happened, but it really explains most of the problems I was having.  I torqued it down really tight.  By doing that, Murphy has assured me that I should break a drive side spoke soon and have to take it back off to fix.  (That is how it works, right?)  The detailer hanger was also a little bent, but I was able to use the crescent wrench to get it back almost perfect.  I’m guessing that this was caused by the travel in plane and van out to my starting point.  After a few shifts to adjust the stops and get indexing centered, I was good as new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3965-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3965-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Sign inside Willis Church&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was wrapping up the bike work, the Pastor came back out and we talked for quite a while.  Then a friend came over and I got to explain all the bike’s “systems”.  I seem to be doing that a lot.  The large 12V NiCad battery pack in the front tube, the 14V solar panel charging the battery, the map dashboard with Off/Low/High beam switches for my headlight powered by the generator hub.  I’m an engineer and a geek.  I can’t help myself.  The Garmin eMap &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; fits right in the center of my “dashboard”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3958-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3958-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 127px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3962-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3962-m.jpg" style="width: 127px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3963-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3963-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 96px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3969-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3969-m.jpg" style="width: 96px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3972-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3972-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Today the route was 156 North.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3971-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3971-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;I never did see the bull.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon I was off.   Again I passed numerous historical plaques.   I got a kick out of the “Caution Bad Bull” sign I saw hanging on a fence, but never found the bull.  They also have signs about the dangers of rail road crossings for trailers.  They do seem to build the train track up higher than I would expect.  I haven’t seen an American Flag outside of the historical places, but I have seen many, many rebel flags.  While not south much geographically, I’m definitely in “The South.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3973-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3973-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Crossing railroad tracks with trailers causes lightning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped at the Fasmart, to scrounge up some vittles for lunch.  Not great fare, including a microwave burrito.  However, they had some fresh fruit, so I left with two bananas in my mesh pocket, after consuming another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3979-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3979-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lunch is served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many more historical signs.  I read a few, but just snapped photos of many to read later.   There weren’t as many touristy place to kill time with today.  It was just standard bicycle touring, but I could tell that we are starting into the hills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3987-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3987-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran across the first historical monument group where you could easily pull over and read with a car, about Savage Station.  I don’t know how they expect people to read others, except for stopping in the middle of the road.  Or bicycle touring, I guess.  It is amazing how much you would miss if you were traveling 30-40 mph faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 158px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3981-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3981-m.jpg" style="width: 158px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 83px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3982-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3982-m.jpg" style="width: 83px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 78px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3983-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3983-m.jpg" style="width: 78px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 82px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3984-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3984-m.jpg" style="width: 82px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3985-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3985-m.jpg" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3986-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3986-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3988-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3988-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My touring rig, fully loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3990-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3990-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took the time to shoot a photo of my touring rig, at the stop.  You can see the charging circuit, under the solar panel.  The 10 D-cell 12V NiCad battery pack (2 wide, 5 long) is attached forward of the front fork, on the main tube.  The blue waterproof bag contains my sleeping bag and Thermorest.  The smaller black bag under that is my tent.  The last bag towards the back is my Mountainsmith pack.  This comes with me everywhere.  It is the bag that still allows me to get home if everything else is stolen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I photographed a few more historical markers about the Seven Days Battles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3992-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3992-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3993-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3993-m.jpg" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 130px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3995-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3995-m.jpg" style="width: 130px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3997-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3997-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3998-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3998-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4000-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4000-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Garthright House Front&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4003-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4003-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Garthright House Rear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped by the Garthright House, used by both sides as a field hospital during the Battle of Cold Harbor.  This is a restored house, but only available for viewing on the outside.  There is no one here to offer tours.   Near the house, soldiers were interned in the family cemetery.  They were later moved to the Cold Harbor Cemetery, across the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 184px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/3999-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/3999-m.jpg" style="width: 184px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4001-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4001-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4004-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4004-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4006-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4006-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 92px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4007-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4007-m.jpg" style="width: 92px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4019-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4019-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The Cold Harbor Cemetery Enterance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4018-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4018-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Tombstone being consumed by a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cold Harbor Cemetery contained bodies of soldiers from so many states.  It is amazing how much death man can cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The withered rock of the tombstones did less to speak to the age of these graves than the single gravestone, consumed by a tree.  I wondered if this was the only gravestone “eaten” by the tree.  It certainly had the width to have completely hidden a stone in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4008-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4008-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4009-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4009-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4010-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4010-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4011-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4011-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4012-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4012-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4013-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4013-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4014-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4014-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4015-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4015-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4016-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4016-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4017-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4017-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4021-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4021-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Cold Harbor Battlefield National Park&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4035-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4035-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Animated light display of battle with vocie narration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t see the full historical significance until I reached the Cold Harbor visitors center and listened to the narrative of the battles and the serious loss of life here. It seems like more often than not, I’m hitting places in reverse order, due to the direction. Hopefully this will even out along the route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4023-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4023-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visitor’s center was very informative and really broke down the battle.   One simple but effective display had animated LEDs along with a voice narrative.  At first, it felt like a High School project, but its simplicity made for an easy to follow explanation, with different colors for each side of the battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 163px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4022-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4022-m.jpg" style="width: 163px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 85px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4024-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4024-m.jpg" style="width: 85px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 132px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4025-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4025-m.jpg" style="width: 132px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 69px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4036-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4036-m.jpg" style="width: 69px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 87px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4041-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4041-m.jpg" style="width: 87px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4037-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4037-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Meeting the Petes for the first time at Cold Harbor Battlefield&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Petes pulled in on their tandem, towing a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BOB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YAK&lt;/span&gt; trailer, just as I was leaving the Cold Harbor Visitor’s Center.  We were both heading for the same campground, so I told them that I would see them there. We talked a little about how their trailer was working.  My first touring setup was a Vision R40 pulling a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YAK&lt;/span&gt; trailer.  That is the best option for a tandem like this, if you can’t get a touring tandem that can handle bags.  I wanted to standardize on one tire size (dual 20” wheels now).  My previous setup had 20” from=nt, 26” rear, and the 16” &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YAK&lt;/span&gt; wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4042-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4042-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;I caught back up with the Petes after my detour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit more riding, I detoured to head into Mechanicsville. I needed to find a Radio Shack to fix my bike computer. I also found out yesterday that I have a blown fuse in battery pack lead, so the solar charger isn’t really doing anything. I have 4 at home, where they are sure to do me loads of good. Oh, I did bring spares.  The wrong ones, as it turns out.  Won’t even fit.  The fuse probably did its job, limiting discharge when something shorted against the charger &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCB&lt;/span&gt; in travel.  So we didnt catch something on fire, but I have not battery pack functionality until I find a replacement fuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught back up with the Petes on the way back to route after an unsuccessful quest for electronics parts.  The traffic started to get pretty bad.  We both pulled off every once in a while to let traffic past.  I took a picture when waiting for a bit and you can barely see the Petes up ahead.  I decided to take a few minutes to go over my route on the map and figure out dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4043-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4043-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Smothering traffic towards the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; for some groceries and started following the map to the campground. On the way, I passed the Petes’ bicycle at a McDonalds. Awful tour food. Either eat at the local hole in the walls or cook your own. That is my plan. That means I’ll probably stop at a McDonalds in the future and make myself a hypocrit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have learned to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEVER&lt;/span&gt; trust the placement of an icon on the maps. I pedaled down the roads that contained the icon for the campground and wound up asking for directions.  After following bad directions, I wound up asking for more.  How can people live 2 miles from a campground and not know it?  I eventually made it to Americamp, my destination for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4045-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4045-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My campsite for the night at Americamp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a site next to the Petes and found out that they were reading the book when I pasted them having dinner in McDonalds.  If I refer to “the book”, I’ll almost always be talking about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/reviews/bicycling-coast-to-coast/"&gt;Bicycling Coast to Coast&lt;/a&gt;.  The route is more explicit in the book.  They took the shorter route (or as some might call it, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIGHT&lt;/span&gt; route.)  I told them the short cut I discovered to get back on route tomorrow, that I used to get back to the campground.  I can also take it in the morning without feeling guilty, being that I will have ridden that part almost twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over all, more than 40 miles instead of the 32 miles I expected, with over a 1000 feet of climbing.  My legs are going to need a rest day pretty soon, and I’m not sure if I can make the 52 miles with another 1000+ feet of climbing tomorrow.  I’ll see what I feel like in the morning.  I’m really wishing that my job didn’t kill me before I left and I actually had time to do some training rides.  I’m getting in shape “on the job”.  That is the beauty of a recumbent.  You don’t have to get your body tuned to dealing with the saddle, just sit in your lawn chair and make your legs go.  Until your legs don’t want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-3/4046-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-3/4046-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My journaling setup with analog modem through StartTac cell phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I included a shot of my laptop and cell phone setup.  The keyboard of the Toshiba Libretto 110 is a little cramped, but usable.  The StarTac connects with a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCMCIA&lt;/span&gt; analog modem.  I’m starting to get faster typing on this smaller keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I sat at a picnic table under a mercury lamp with my power cord plugged into the pole, a few thoughts came into mind.  It is a wonderful thing to find a shower after a day out riding, as I know days will come when they won’t be available.  It is a handy thing to find a power outlet, especially when you battery pack is non-functional.  It is amazing how hard a chocolate bar can be when it is this cold.  It is harder to break and longer to get going in your mouth.  But it still taste the same once it starts melting. Yummy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 2 - Berkley Plantation</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-2-berkley/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-21T02:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-21:blog/trans-am/day-2-berkley/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3921-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3921-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3923-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3923-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Drive into Berkley Plantation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berkley Plantation was my second stop of the day.  I should point out to anyone wanting to try this route themselves that the 1/2 mile ride into Berkley is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TERRIBLE&lt;/span&gt;.  You see the sign that asks you to enjoy yourself for the next 1/2 mile of authentic Colonial road and you get to try as hard as you can to keep the bike upright.  That is one of the toughest roads I have ever ridden on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3922-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3922-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Stones making up the wobbly road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a gravel road with very round rocks.  The rocks very in size from sand to 4 inches.  Did I mention the 5-15 degrees of slope for drainage?  That is good for flipping your back wheel out whenever it feels like it.  Yee-haw, I have now surfed a bike and am immensely impressed with myself for not going down once.  This surfing experience would prove almost enough practice for a situation later in the trip, but we will have to wait for that.  Despite the challenge getting in and out, I believe the ride was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3879-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3879-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the site of the first official Thanksgiving in 1619.  Benjamin Harrison &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IV&lt;/span&gt; built the mansion on the land in 1726 and married Anne Carter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3916-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3916-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the birthplace of Benjamin Harrison V, a signer of the Declaration of Independence.  This was also the birthplace of William Henry Harrison, the ninth president of the United States, and ancestrial home of his grandson, Benjamin Harrison, the twenty-third President.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Civil War, the plantation was occupied by General George McClellan’s Union troops.  General Daniel Butterfield composed “Taps”, played by his bugler, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;O.W.&lt;/span&gt; Norton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture is original and the furnishings are of the period when it was built.  The basement contains a mini museum, with paintings and exhibits describing the history of the plantation.  This also was a tour worth seeing, given by enthusiastic guides in period outfits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3857-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3857-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 115px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3858-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3858-m.jpg" style="width: 115px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 131px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3861-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3861-m.jpg" style="width: 131px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3862-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3862-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 116px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3863-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3863-m.jpg" style="width: 116px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3872-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3872-m.jpg" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3856-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3856-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 74px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3893-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3893-m.jpg" style="width: 74px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3876-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3876-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3874-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3874-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Showing the date of construction for the residence, 1726.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour guide mentioned that we take a look at the cement medalian on the side of the house placed by Benjamin Harrison &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IV&lt;/span&gt; when the mansion was built in 1726.  I took a wide and close up picture of those.  I took more pictures around the buildings on my way to see the landing site of the first Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 132px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3877-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3877-m.jpg" style="width: 132px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3878-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3878-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 87px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3880-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3880-m.jpg" style="width: 87px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3881-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3881-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 117px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3882-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3882-m.jpg" style="width: 117px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3885-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3885-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3886-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3886-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 68px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3888-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3888-m.jpg" style="width: 68px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3889-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3889-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3904-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3904-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3913-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3913-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3905-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3905-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3908-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3908-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3909-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3909-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 71px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3914-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3914-m.jpg" style="width: 71px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3901-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3901-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Replica of part of the Margaret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3900-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3900-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;View out of the James River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South through the gardens and towards the James River, we come upon the monument, ship diagram, and part replica of the ship that carried 38 to land here in 1619.  About 20 miles upstream of this point, Jamestown was established on May 14, 1607.  More information is available in the signs I photographed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 60px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3892-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3892-m.jpg" style="width: 60px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3894-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3894-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 105px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3895-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3895-m.jpg" style="width: 105px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 68px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3903-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3903-m.jpg" style="width: 68px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 131px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3906-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3906-m.jpg" style="width: 131px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 95px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3917-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/berkley/3917-m.jpg" style="width: 95px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="side-trip"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 2 - Sherwood Forest Plantation</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-2-sherwood-forest/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-21T01:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-21:blog/trans-am/day-2-sherwood-forest/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3783-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3783-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Sign from Hwy 5 (John Tyler Memorial Highway)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sherwood Forest was the first plantation I visited today along Hwy 5.  It holds a few distinctions, such as the only private residence having been owned by two unrelated presidents.  William Henry Harrison inherited the property in 1790 and sold it in 1793 without having every lived in the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3784-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3784-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Center portion of the main house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where John Tyler, the tenth (1841-1845) President of the United States retired, after purchasing the property in 1842.  Sherwood Forest Plantation has been owned by the Tyler family continuously, since John Tyler purchased it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3788-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3788-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Rear center of the main house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 1616 land grant, this plantation was called Smith’s Hundred.  Sometime the name was changed to Walnut Grove, showing reference to many trees on the property.  The house was built in 1720 and is a classic example of Virginia Tidewater design.  This consists of a large house, small house, and kitchen.  It had many owners until Tyler purchased the home and 1,600 acres in 1842.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3789-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3789-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Overseer’s House&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he purchased the property from his cousin, Collier Minge, he was still in the White House.  He renamed the plantation to “Sherwood Forest” as a reference to his reputation as a political outlaw by the Whig party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3817-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3817-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Shot down the length of the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house originally had two separate out buildings, because doing wash and preparing food required fire.  It is much nicer to have a kitchen or laundry burn down than lose the entire residence.  These three buildings were eventually joined with great halls.  Unfortunately, no photography is allowed inside the home.  The tour contained many interesting artifacts, beautiful furniture, and grand rooms.  It is definitely worth taking if you come to the property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3825-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3825-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half of the home is currently an actual residence, so you are not allowed to see the entire building.  However, one hall is part of the tour and you can see how it was laid out to accommodate the popular dance of the time: the Virginia Reel.  Due to these halls joining the home into one structure, it has the distinction of being one of the longest private residences in the country at 300 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3827-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3827-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Tyler was the first vice president to fill the role of presidency after the death of William Henry Harrison.  He was previously twice Governor or Virginia, a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; Senator, a member of the House of Representatives, a Virginia state senator, and Viriginia House delegate.  He re-entered public service as a member of the Confederate Congress of the COnfederate States of America in 1861.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3829-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3829-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sherwood Forest was damaded during the Civil War by Union soldiers in 1864.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3831-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3831-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grounds holds more than eighty varieties of trees, in the 25 acres of serence woodlands, terraced gardens and lawn.  Many trees are hundreds of years old and 29 not indigenous to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;.  This includes a gingko tree given to Tyler by Captain Matthew Perry returning from the Orient in the 1850s.  This retintroduced gingko trees to America.  The walking tour of all the various species is a nice diversion around the grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Smoke House was used from 1740’s to mid 20th century for curing hams.  The plantation provided all the food for the family, house servants, and field hands.  At butchering time, meats were bedded in salt, hung from the rafters and smoked by smoldering hickory logs behind selaed doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 102px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3790-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3790-m.jpg" style="width: 102px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3791-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3791-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3792-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3792-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Shingle Maker was patented in 1878.  Local cypress trees used to make shingles for all buildings on the plantation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 127px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3794-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3794-m.jpg" style="width: 127px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3796-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3796-m.jpg" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 153px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3798-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3798-m.jpg" style="width: 153px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Wine House was originally used for curing tobacco leaves.  It was build around 1660.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 104px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3800-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3800-m.jpg" style="width: 104px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 72px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3802-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3802-m.jpg" style="width: 72px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The outhouse has three different seats.  I guess women going to the bathroom in pairs goes back further than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 137px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3803-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3803-m.jpg" style="width: 137px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3804-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3804-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3805-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3805-m.jpg" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Milk House and interior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 108px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3819-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3819-m.jpg" style="width: 108px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3820-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3820-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 134px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3821-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3821-m.jpg" style="width: 134px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Law Office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3818-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/sherwood-forest/3818-m.jpg" style="width: 75px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="side-trip"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 2 - Jamestown to Glendale, VA</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-21:blog/trans-am/day-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3761-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3761-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Loaded and ready to go, once I stow my drying shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a good night’s sleep, despite the temperature.  I thought about not bringing my 20 degree bag and purchasing a warmer weather bag to take up less space and weight.  I’m thrilled that I didn’t talk myself into it.  I needed every bit of that bag to stay warm last night.  I woke just before 7, refreshed and with my headache gone.  I’m sure that drinking water throughout the night helped counter the dehydration and altitude effects.  I immediately went to get my $22 worth of hot shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3756-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3756-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;First campsite of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing my campsite for the first time in the light assured that I didn’t do too bad of a job picking it out.  The layer of pine needles and leaves added a nice soft accentuation to the Thermorest air mattress.  I setup my laptop and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AA&lt;/span&gt; batteries to charge in the outlets along the wall of the restroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sky was hard overcast in the early morning, so I wondered about today’s weather.  I tuned in the local &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOAA&lt;/span&gt; weather band station and listened to the monotonous voice repeating the current and forecasted weather.  The report kept using the phrase “unseasonably cool”.  Yes, I’d agree with that.  The forecast was partly cloudy with a chance of light showers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3757-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3757-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Getting my oatmeal breakfast going on my camp stove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small radio I brought along with me can receive all &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOAA&lt;/span&gt; weather radio stations, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FM&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; station audio.  I knew that I would be in some places far from civilization and thought it my best chance if getting useful information on the trip.  Like my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, Camera, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; player it runs on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AA&lt;/span&gt;’s.  My 4 bay charger for the NiMH &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AA&lt;/span&gt;’s runs off of 12V, either directly from my large NiCd pack on the bike frame, or via an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt; wall adaptor.  My Libretto laptop also charges off of 12V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3758-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3758-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Eating breakfast and listening to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPR&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I switched to Morning Edition on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPR&lt;/span&gt; and started oatmeal on the stove.  It was a cold morning and I didn’t move very fast, because I didn’t relish the thought of adding a 12 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MPH&lt;/span&gt; wind chill to the current temperature when I started riding.  I mixed a sports drink from some powder and wished I had thought to pack a tea bag or hot chocolate.  But then I thought this was the start of summer and I would only want cool drinks.  The oatmeal with raisins was tasty.  Their addition of heat inside me was even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3759-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3759-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Pecked open hole in bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pre-packed some oatmeal in the snack sized Ziploc bags, before I left.  This was about the right size for a morning meal.  As I left to clean up the pot, one of these bags full of oatmeal sat on the picnic table.   I spent at most 3 minutes in the restroom, which was enough time for a crow to peck into a bag and start eating my oatmeal.  Glad I still had the first bag, I dumped the remaining oatmeal in there and chuckled.  A very fast opportunistic scavenger.  He was able to get quite a bit down, and even more scattered around the table where he will be able to claim once I’m gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3764-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3764-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gradually finished breaking down camp and getting ready for the day.  I left the campground just before 10, starting my first real touring day.  I stopped at the camp store to pick up some snacks on the way out.  The trick is to carry enough so you don’t go hungry, but every bit you carry is going up every hill you meet.  So you error only slightly on the side of too many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3766-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3766-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;First Route 76 sign I saw during the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My route followed highway 5 towards Richmond for a majority of the day.  I was still in a somewhat high population area and there was a considerable amount of dump truck and semi-truck traffic along the road in both directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most drivers were courteous, I’m sure having seen quite a few Trans-Am bicycle tourists over the years.  A couple people passed when it wasn’t really safe, but a few always do.  I waved at all the truckers I passed, trying to build up my trucker karma for those nasty coal trucks I keep hearing about in eastern Kentucky.  I’m surprised that I haven’t seen a dog yet.  In 80 miles of cycling that is pretty strange.  I guess I will have to wait for those infamous eastern Kentucky dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3773-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3773-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SS&lt;/span&gt; Sub Shop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to learn something positive about eastern Kentucky, as those are the only two things I know about it:  terrible trucks with bad drivers and terrible dogs.  That is the only thing bicycle tourists riding through there talk about.  I’m determined to find something nice about the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3772-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3772-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lunch for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning was the first time I noticed the 76 bike route signs, marking the Bikecentennial route I was riding, started in 1976.  I started taking some pictures of the sign when I spotted them.
I still have the chance to head back to Williamsburg, but I didn’t even consider it.  I wanted to get further away from the traffic and on my way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3847-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3847-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had considered stopping to have a few of the snacks I picked up at the camp store and was happy to see the sub shop at 11:30.  I devoured a pretty good hot turkey and cheese sub, fries and a Pepsi.  I told myself I would eat better on this trip, but it was really good!  With each stop, the basics are always handled.  Fill up your water bottles and get rid of the water you drank during the last couple hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3769-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3769-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;I’ve got a few miles to Richmond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 249px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3765-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3765-s.jpg" style="width: 249px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had seen the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OFF&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OFF&lt;/span&gt; at restaurants and stores during my two days in Virginia.  I wound up researching this after the trip was over and leanred that it stands for Alcoholic Beverage Control.  Apparently, after prohibition ended, states came up with various systems to tax and control alcoholic beverage sales.  In an alcoholic beverage control state, the state is essentially a monopoly and operates stores where retailers can purchase their liquor to sell.  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt; means the location has a license to sell alcohol for consumption on the premises.  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OFF&lt;/span&gt; means the location can sell alcohol for you to take away.  While interesting to figure out, this really didn’t concern me much, not being a drinker of much stronger than soda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3768-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3768-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Charles City County, perhaps one of the most confusing County names I’ve come across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop was Sherwood Forest Plantation in Charles City County.  This is the first of 4 major and many minor Plantations within 14 miles along highway 5.  See the upcoming side trip post for more information and pictures.  I spent about an hour touring the grounds before heading out again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3844-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3844-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Half of the father/daughter team that pass me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was passed by a father and daughter team, also doing the Trans-Am.  They were running light for the first day, with no bags.  They mentioned that a vehicle was bringing them.  I didn’t gather if they were heading all the way unloaded, or just for the start.  Either way, I will probably never catch back up with them.  Loaded touring is much more effort than doing joined day rides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then stopped at Berkley Plantation, directly on the James River.  This land is home to many of America’s firsts, including the first Thanksgiving on Dec. 4th, 1619.  See the side trip post for more details of this visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3767-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3767-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left the Berkley Plantation after 5:30 and headed to Glendale.  I stopped on the way to pick up some food for dinner.  This has been an interesting transition already.  The grocery stores available are a far cry from the huge supermarkets we get used to in modern life.  Tonight’s dinner was plucked from a small gas station and grocery.  The selection was poor, but the cyclist was hungry.  Hunger makes anything taste great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3955-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3955-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The residence of the Methodist minister, a landmark of the Battle of Malvern Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En route to Willis United Methodist Church, I stopped at the location for the last of the Seven Days Battles, Malvern Hill.  It is amazing how dense history is packed along this stretch of road.  That was a large factor of why this route was chosen for the Trans-Am trail during the planning in 1974-5.  What I am seeing is only a small fraction of what is around.  While riding a bike, it is a simple thing to pull off and read a sign noting some historical significance.  Nearly all of these would have been missed in a car and the small paragraph on each sign doesn’t come close to covering the historical significance of the location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 98px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3938-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3938-m.jpg" style="width: 98px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 70px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3940-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3940-m.jpg" style="width: 70px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 95px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3941-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3941-m.jpg" style="width: 95px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 103px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3943-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3943-m.jpg" style="width: 103px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 101px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3948-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3948-m.jpg" style="width: 101px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 109px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3950-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3950-m.jpg" style="width: 109px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 154px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3944-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3944-m.jpg" style="width: 154px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3946-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3946-m.jpg" style="width: 133px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 154px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3947-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3947-m.jpg" style="width: 154px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 104px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3951-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3951-m.jpg" style="width: 104px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3954-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3954-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Willis Church Historical Plaque&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastor Manning Harrell was a wonderful host, when I pulled into the Church around 8:30.  We had a chance to chat, while I was setting up camp.  He is retiring at the end of this month, and he has really enjoyed meeting all the cyclists in the five years he has been at the church.  Apparently the new pastor is also excited about hosting cyclists, so this fine overnight stop on the trail will be going strong for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="floatclear"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some historical signs along the route today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 108px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3763-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3763-m.jpg" style="width: 108px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 102px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3777-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3777-m.jpg" style="width: 102px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3778-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3778-m.jpg" style="width: 81px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 134px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3779-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3779-m.jpg" style="width: 134px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 116px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3780-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3780-m.jpg" style="width: 116px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 106px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3851-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3851-m.jpg" style="width: 106px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 108px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3924-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3924-m.jpg" style="width: 108px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 93px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3925-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3925-m.jpg" style="width: 93px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 111px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3926-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3926-m.jpg" style="width: 111px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 99px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-2/3929-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-2/3929-m.jpg" style="width: 99px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 1 - Yorktown to Jamestown, VA</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-20:blog/trans-am/day-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3710-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3710-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Dave Knight (left) and my dad (right) about to pilot the Baron from Bowman Field in Louisville, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KY&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle tourist is greeted with two choices when starting their tour.  Do I ride away from my home or pack up everything and take alternate transportation to the start?  For local tours, the loop method is a good idea.  Start off in one direction and ride in a big loop until you end up back home.  If I had a year’s time, not just a couple months, I would enjoy a loop tour of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;.  It would be ideal to leave Indiana, riding in the northern states during the warmer months and the southern states during the cooler months.  Unfortunately, I didn’t have the few extra weeks it would take to get to Virginia.  My dad has some good flying friends with access to a large enough plane to get us out to the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3717-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3717-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A cruising altitude in the Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave is a part owner of a Baron twin engine aircraft with enough space for me, my father, Dave, and my gear.  Dad and I arrived at Bowman Field in Louisville, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KY&lt;/span&gt; around noon.  We loaded up the plane as soon as Dave arrived.  The local Air Traffic Controllers allowed us to depart a little past 1 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day had a dreary cast, under a solid fluffy blanket of clouds.  An occasional mist hit the windshield and we sampled small rain showers, on the climb to our cruising altitude.  Due to icing at our intended altitude of 11,000 feet, Dave asked for and was cleared up to 13,000 feet.  The Baron is not a pressurized cabin, so air pressure inside is the same as the air pressure outside.  This requires oxygen for the pilot, above 10,000 feet.  Oxygen is required for other members of the plane for altitudes above 14,000 feet for short times and lower altitudes for longer durations.  There were only two sets of oxygen, so Dad and I switched off.  I went more without than with, because Dad wanted to do some of the flying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gave me a chance to practice a pressure breathing technique I had read about for those entering high altitude environments without supplemental oxygen.  The problem isn’t with the percentage of oxygen in the air at higher altitudes; it is a problem with the pressure of the air in your lungs.  The lower pressure means less total volume of air, and therefore less total volume of oxygen.  The low pressure also doesn’t help with pressing the oxygen molecules into your blood stream via your lungs.  The pressure of air in your lungs can be increased by forcing your lips together, while your diaphragm muscles force the air out.  This technique would later prove beneficial when climbing over Hoosier Pass in the Rocky Mountains.  It helped things somewhat, but I was always ready for the oxygen when it was offered.  There were a few times that I became slightly woozy, with just the very beginning stages of hypoxia.  It was an interesting experience, which gave me a headache that would last the rest of the day.  My slight dehydration was also a co-conspiritor in my cranial crankiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience of flying over mountains I would soon see again was somewhat surreal.  The entire trip out took around 2 hours by plane.  The trip back to passing within 50 miles of home would take almost a month by bicycle.  Just when we descended through the cloud layer and opened up many photo worth scenes, I realized my spare batteries were packed out of reach in the back.  My camera went dead as Newport News Airport came within view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3719-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3719-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Unloading the plane at the Newport News Airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shot am most annoyed for missing was the giant aircraft carrier.  It was a beautiful view and seemed bigger than the grass strip in Scottsburg, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IN&lt;/span&gt;, where dad taught me how to land our Aeronica Champ.  An F-18 is quite a different animal, with a stall speed nearly 5 times that number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed at the Newport New Airport just after 3 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;.  After taxing to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FBO&lt;/span&gt; (Fixed Base Operator, the “gas station” of an airport), we began unloading my bike and gear.  It took a few minutes to reassemble everything and get ready to ride over to the start.  Instead of doing that, one of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FBO&lt;/span&gt; employees was nice enough to give me a ride to the Yorktown Visitor’s Center.  So I loaded the bike into a van and went for a quick 9 mile ride.  By the end of the day, I was really happy that I didn’t need to spend almost an hour doing this ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3720-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3720-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bike loaded and ready to tour, with one exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a second time assembling and loading the bike, then checking over everything, I was off to find the Victory Monument (official start of the Trans-American trail).  I stopped 100 feet later.  I couldn’t get my bike computer to work.  I hoped the sensor just got bumped away from the magnet on the spoke.  Any experienced cyclist has run into that one a few times.  I moved the magnet until it made a slight “whack” sound on the sensor, then backed away every so slightly.  But I still had no speed indicated, so that wasn’t the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remembered having to unwind the handlebars after we set the bike down out of the van.  Sure enough, the computer wires were ripped raggedly apart.  I’ll be in need of my first repair sooner than expected.  Anyone know where I can borrow a soldering iron, a little wire, and some heat shrink?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3721-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3721-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Timer based shot at the Victory Monument, with camera sitting on the ground due to unreliable “helpers”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3732-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3732-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Top of the Victory Monument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took some pictures at the Monument before heading for Williamsburg.  I attempted to get another tourist to take a picture of me, but could not locate anything when I reviewed the screen after they left.  I set it all up and they just needed to press the button.  I immediately saw the advantages of bringing a digital camera.  Had I been shooting film, I would have assumed the picture of my overweight self would have already been taken at the monument.  I learned how to use the self timer for the first time and a few seconds later I had the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3722-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3722-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 223px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3723-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3723-m.jpg" style="width: 223px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 212px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3724-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3724-m.jpg" style="width: 212px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3727-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3727-m.jpg" style="width: 79px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3729-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3729-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 231px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3726-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3726-m.jpg" style="width: 231px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 197px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3728-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3728-m.jpg" style="width: 197px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3730-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3730-m.jpg" style="width: 80px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3735-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3735-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Ceremonial dipping of the tire in the… man this bike is heavy, nevermind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just past the Victory Monument, there is a road that doesn’t allow motor vehicles.  I found the first benefit of bicycle touring.  I rode along the 7 houses built over 200 years ago, when Yorktown was Virginia’s leading seaport.  Cannon fire damaged many of the buliding during the Seige of Yorktown, the last major land battle of the Revolutionary War, which ended on October 19, 1781.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3736-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3736-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;George Washington Memorial Highway (Hwy 17) crossing over the York River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After riders start at the Victory Monument, it is ceremonial to dip your back wheel in the York River as the Atlantic Ocean representative body of water.  I thought about that.  I tried to lift my bike.  I thought about carrying my bike over the sand and back.  Then I considered unloading it and making that slightly easier.  Then I just took another picture from a different angle and called it good.  I probably would have done it, if I had more time in the day.  But time was moving, so I needed to as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3740-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3740-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Entering Colonial Parkway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colonists named this river first Charles and then York, both as an honor to the Duke of York.  It was known to the Indians of the region as Pamunkey, a name still used by a smaller tributary of the York River today.  While only 26 miles in length, the tidal waters of the York River flow over the deepest natural channel of any Chesapeake Bay tributary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3741-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3741-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mileage signs come so much slower than in a car, so I got excited each time I saw one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the York River is the site of Werowocomoco, an Indian village that was Powhatan’s “chiefest habitation” in the early period of the Jamestown settlement.  This was the location that John Smith was held prisoner in 1607.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride was really beautiful, but there were so many things to see that I needed to ride right past.  It was after 4 o’clock, with only 4 hours of sunlight left, and I had no clue where I was going to stay tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3745-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3745-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would learn that it is often easier to find places to stay in less congested areas (other than motels and hotels).  In the big cities, cars are king.  So was it most places here.  I pulled into the Williamsburg Visitor’s Center around 6:30, as everything was closing down.  I received pointers to the lower priced hotels in the area and where the restaurants were hiding.  My lunch wasn’t large before I left Jeffersonville and I was famished.  I found a Golden Corral.  There is a reason why there are few “All You Can Eat” buffets along the Trans-Am trail.  A cyclist can burn thousands of extra calories a day.  And buffets can go out of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3751-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3751-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restaurant was breathing tourists in and out as I ate and read about the route ahead.  They all seemed to be taking their first gasps of vacation, after the school year finished.  As long as the food doesn’t run out, the best you can hope for is a busy buffet.  Food turned over faster, tastes better.  Hunger also has that effect on food.  While I enjoyed resting, reading, and people watching, I knew daylight was fading.  My choices were hotel or not.  The hotels were right here.  If I stayed in a hotel or motel, I could ride back into Williamsburg for a visit tomorrow.  But this is a bicycle tour, not a tourist trip.  I wanted to be some miles under my belt and away from all the people and traffic, so off I rode into the fading daylight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3752-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3752-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left the restaurant a little after 8 towards Jamestown.  This was the best option I could come up with for the night.  Soon the darkness pushed back the day and stopped to rig for night riding.  I turned on my rear lights and flipped the switch on my “dashboard” to enable the headlight.  I knew these were going to be needed through out the trip, but didn’t think I’d be riding into the night during the first day out.  I finally pulled into the campground after 9 and was greeted with a $22 campsite!  That is quite a bit of dough for a plot of grass and the use of a shower and bathroom.  Supply and demand was in full force in Jamestown.  While I knew $22 wasn’t the most I would spend for a night, as I planned a few motel stays, I hoped it was the most I would ever spend for a campsite.  Oh well, where else am I gonna go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-1/3754-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-1/3754-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Faking sleep to take a picture on my outfit for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my tent pitched and shower taken, I fired up my little Libretto laptop and started typing up today’s journal entry.  This little laptop is about the size of a Disney packaged &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; movie.  The keyboard is smaller than normal and I had not yet adjusted to it.  The headache still hung around as I typed up my day’s journal, so I constantly sipped on water.  The color of my urine had assured me that I was still dehydrated or someone slipped a bunch of vitamin B into my food at the Golden Corral.  I assumed the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night was unseasonably cold.  Temperatures dropped to 34 over night.  My 20 degree mummy bag felt nice over the small Thermarest air mattress.  The full hood was too warm, but a small fleece cap was just right.  With my water bottles available for sipping a few times through out the night, I slept well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="bicycle"></category><category term="touring"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 0 - Final Shakedown Ride</title><link href="http://www.joesacher.com/blog/trans-am/day-0/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joe Sacher</name></author><id>tag:www.joesacher.com,2002-05-19:blog/trans-am/day-0/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-0/3659-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-0/3659-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I completely loaded up my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RANS&lt;/span&gt; Rocket.  I’ve built many custom components to make it into a cross-country touring machine.  Unfortunately, I haven’t had as much time getting ready for the trip as I wanted.  Work pressed into taking far too much of my time, so both equipment and physical shape preparation was lacking.  I will just have to get in shape by doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="figure align-right" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-0/3660-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-0/3660-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this lack of preparation chewed up almost two weeks of my time off.  I spent a week getting my belongings into storage and moved out of my apartment.  I spent another week finishing equipment builds and other touring builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;a data-fluidbox="" href="/images/trans-am/day-0/3664-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/trans-am/day-0/3664-s.jpg" style="width: 256px; height: auto; max-width: 100%;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also finished up the code for my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; based email journal and mailing list.  It may be hard to connect over the analog modem through my Star-Tac cell phone, even just to send updates.  So, hopefully I won’t have to fix code while on the road.  I can currently compose updates as an email to a certain address, which will post and distribute them when the email is sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I will be flying out to Newport News Airport and making my way to the start of this adventure.  After more than two years of planning, it is really nice to get this started.  Hopefully I will think the same thing a week or two into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll see you on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="trans-am"></category><category term="touring"></category><category term="travelogue"></category></entry></feed>