<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nonfiction on joesacher.com</title>
    <link>http://www.joesacher.com/tags/nonfiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nonfiction on joesacher.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2002-2017 - Joe Sacher - All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.joesacher.com/tags/nonfiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing by Stephen King</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2008/07/03/on-writing-by-stephen-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2008/07/03/on-writing-by-stephen-king/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve started writing again. In the last few years, all my writing was on screenplay style for short films. Some of these we actually shot and produced, most just sit on my computer in final PDF form. Writing in screenplay format is different than novel, novella, or short story forms. Screenplay is all about dialog and character actions. There is no exposition of character thoughts. I think this experience makes you a stronger dialog writer, when you switch to fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycling Coast to Coast by Donna Ikenberry</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/12/15/bicycling-coast-to-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/12/15/bicycling-coast-to-coast/</guid>
      <description>As soon as I realized that my recumbent would allow me to complete my dream of riding a bicycle across the country, I started research all over the web. While reading through the many trip reports of coast to coast touring cyclists, two things became clear.
First, I would be riding the TransAmerica Trail created by Adventure Cycling in 1976 (the year of my birth).
Second, I should purchase, read, re-read, and take along Donna&amp;rsquo;s book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metal Cowboy by Joe Kurmaskie</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/11/04/metal-cowboy-by-joe-kurmaskie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/11/04/metal-cowboy-by-joe-kurmaskie/</guid>
      <description>I have not found a way to better describe this book than the first sentence inside the dust cover. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s as if Dave Barry and Charles Kuralt squeezed together onto a bicycle to pedal across America and around the world, filing outrageous dispatches along the way.&amp;rdquo;
Indeed, many times while reading I felt as if I was watching the well done Sunday morning stories where the common man or the small town are shown in all of their glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Code Book by Simon Singh</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/03/23/the-code-book-by-simon-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/03/23/the-code-book-by-simon-singh/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, you can no longer win $15,000 by reading this book. It was the announcement of the solution to the 10 cipher challenges, located in the back of The Code Book, that made me aware of this book. Money aside, if you are interested in learning of the history of codes and ciphers, this book is for you!
Did you know that Mary Queens of Scots was killed by Queen Elizabeth, because her code was not strong enough to foil the code breakers of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sew and Repair Your Outdoor Gear by Louise Lindgren</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/02/14/sew-and-repair-your-outdoor-gear-by-louise-lindgren/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2007/02/14/sew-and-repair-your-outdoor-gear-by-louise-lindgren/</guid>
      <description>I really wish I had ran into this book before I purchased my &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo; sewing machine. I got a no frills home machine with a few stitches. It was a floor model, but I would have been better to spend the money on a light weight industrial sewing machine with only a straight stitch. Louise was talking about me when she mentioned those who buy a machine with all of these cool stitches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bicycle Wheel by Jobst Brandt</title>
      <link>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2002/03/02/the-bicycle-wheel-by-jobst-brandt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joesacher.com/blog/2002/03/02/the-bicycle-wheel-by-jobst-brandt/</guid>
      <description>I have just finished building my first rear wheel using The Bicycle Wheel as a guide. This book will teach you the technical aspects of the bicycle wheel in both structural principles and practical methods. After a couple hundred miles on my new wheel, it is still true as an arrow.
This book debunks myths and gives you the confidence to repair, build, and rebuild wheels. I can honestly say that I no longer fear any wheel repairs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>